<Table>
<Row><Cell>game_over_basicTraining</Cell><Cell>You've lost the trust of Sir Radzig.</Cell><Cell>Sör Radzig'in güveninin kaybettin.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_conquest_fled</Cell><Cell>Without your help, Istvan won the Battle of Talmberg.</Cell><Cell>Yardımın olmadan Istvan, Talmberg Savaşı'nı kazandı.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_conquest_follow_capon</Cell><Cell>Without getting help, your father died.</Cell><Cell>Yardım almadan baban öldü.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_counteroffensive_reinforcements</Cell><Cell>You didn't get the reinforcements to Vranik from Talmberg.</Cell><Cell>Takviyeleri Talmberg'den Vranik'e götüremedin.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_bleeding</Cell><Cell>You have bled to death.</Cell><Cell>Kanamadan öldün.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_collision</Cell><Cell>You have died.</Cell><Cell>Öldün.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_fall</Cell><Cell>You have fallen to your death.</Cell><Cell>Düşerek öldün.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_poison</Cell><Cell>You have been poisoned.</Cell><Cell>Zehirlendin.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_scripted_hit</Cell><Cell>You were murdered under unforseen circumstances.</Cell><Cell>Fark edilmeyen nedenlerden öldürüldün.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_self_harm</Cell><Cell>You have died by your own hand.</Cell><Cell>Kendini öldürdün.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_starving</Cell><Cell>You have starved to death. </Cell><Cell>Açlıktan öldün.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_in_combat</Cell><Cell>You have died in combat.</Cell><Cell>Muharebede öldün.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_in_jail</Cell><Cell>You have died in jail.</Cell><Cell>Hapiste öldün.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_unknown</Cell><Cell>You have died.</Cell><Cell>Öldün.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_E3_lost</Cell><Cell>You have lost the battle.</Cell><Cell>Savaşı kaybettin.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_E3_win</Cell><Cell>You are victorious!</Cell><Cell>Galip geldin!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_escape_skalitz</Cell><Cell>You've been hit by a stray Cuman arrow.</Cell><Cell>Serseri bir Kuman oku sana isabet etti.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_escape_talmberk</Cell><Cell>Robard is really angry at you right now.</Cell><Cell>Robard şu an sana çok kızgın.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_finished</Cell><Cell>Game finished</Cell><Cell>Oyun bitti</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_killed_by_zmola</Cell><Cell>Zmola killed you while you were unconscious.</Cell><Cell>Baygınken Zmola seni öldürdü.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_killed_while_unconscious</Cell><Cell>You were killed while unconscious.</Cell><Cell>Baygınken öldürüldün.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_lostBattle</Cell><Cell>You lost the battle.</Cell><Cell>Savaşı kaybettin.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_night_rescue_crime</Cell><Cell>You committed treachery!</Cell><Cell>Hainlik ettin.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_night_rescue_ran_away</Cell><Cell>Young Lord Capon died while attempting to rescue the hostages.</Cell><Cell>Genç Lord Capon rehineleri kurtarmaya çalışırken öldü.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_nights_watch</Cell><Cell>You've been kicked out of the Bailiff's service for incompetence.</Cell><Cell>Yetersizlikten dolayı Kâhya'nın hizmetinden çıkarıldın.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_ptacek_bled</Cell><Cell>Capon lost 5 pints of blood. His goose is cooked.</Cell><Cell>Capon 2,5 litre kan kaybetti. Kazı ise yemek oldu.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_revelation_killing_inquisitor_text</Cell><Cell>Murdering a servant of God is a most heinous crime! You tried to flee, but they soon caught up with you. Sir Radzig turned his back on you and you were hanged for your crime. Johanka was convicted of heresy and died as a result of her punishment.</Cell><Cell>Tanrı'nın hizmetkârını öldürmek ne büyük suçtur! Kaçmaya çalıştın ancak seni yakaladılar. Sör Radzig sana yüz çevirdi ve suçun sebebiyle asıldın. Johanka kâfirlikten suçlu bulundu ve cezası gereği öldürüldü.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_revelation_killing_inquisitor_undercover_seen_text</Cell><Cell>You were seen killing the Inquisitor and the law soon caught up with you. Sir Radzig turned his back on you and you were hanged for your crime.</Cell><Cell>Engizisyoncuyu öldürürken görüldün ve kanun seni yakaladı. Sör Radzig sana yüz çevirdi ve suçun sebebiyle asıldın.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_revelation_speking_heresy_text</Cell><Cell>You died after your tongue was cut out for heretical speeches. Johanka was also convicted of heresy and suffered the same fate.</Cell><Cell>Kafirce konuşmlarından ötürü dilin kesildikten sonra öldün. Johanka da kâfirlikten suçlu bulundu ve seninle aynı kaderi paylaştı.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_run</Cell><Cell>A village lad like you has no chance of defeating the fearsome Cumans. Better to run and save your skin.</Cell><Cell>A village lad like you has no chance of defeating the fearsome Cumans. Better to run and save your skin.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_simek_text</Cell><Cell>Samuel died.</Cell><Cell>Samuel öldü.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_tereza_escape</Cell><Cell>You were hit by a stray Cuman arrow and died while trying to flee.</Cell><Cell>You were hit by a stray Cuman arrow and died while trying to flee.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_tereza_prison</Cell><Cell>You've been executed for your grave crimes. May God have mercy on your sinful soul.</Cell><Cell>You've been executed for your grave crimes. May God have mercy on your sinful soul.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_test</Cell><Cell>TEST</Cell><Cell>TEST</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_thank_you</Cell><Cell>Thank you for playing!</Cell><Cell>Oynadığın için teşekkürler!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc2_sch2_GhfW_e1050_G8Y7</Cell><Cell>Replace</Cell><Cell>Değiştir</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc2_sch2_GhfW_e1051_XHhc</Cell><Cell>Bury</Cell><Cell>Göm</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc2_sch2_GhfW_e1210_8zxc</Cell><Cell>Colour the water</Cell><Cell>Suyu renklendir.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc2_sch2_GhfW_e1508_DCgh</Cell><Cell>Throw</Cell><Cell>At</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc3_sch8_9v0p_e20_O9rb</Cell><Cell>Travelling the roads in the province is hazardous - merchants are afraid even to stick their noses out of the inns, visiting relatives in neighbouring villages is a life or death gamble and folk living in remote farmsteads sleep with axes under their pillows. Behind any oak or ash along the wayside, there may be a ruthless bandit lying in wait, or even a poor student, who has drunk away his last Groschen and entered the spirit of these lawless times. Either way, the victim is lucky to lose only his purse, and not his head. </Cell><Cell>Bölgeler arası seyahat etmek oldukça tehlikeli öyle ki -  satıcılar hanlardan dışarı çıkmak istemiyor, komşu köylerdeki akrabaları ziyarete gitmek tam bir ölüm kalım kumarı ve yerleşim yerine uzak çiftliklerde yaşayan insanlar yastıklarının altında baltalar ile uyuyorlar. Acımasız bir haydut ya da son groşenini içkiye vermiş bir ve kanun tanımayan bir öğrenci, yol kenarındaki bir ağacın veya çalılığın arkasına pusuya yatmış olabilir. Her halükarda, kurban kafası yerine sadece cüzdanını kaybederse şanslı sayılır.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc3_sch8_9v0p_e21_Nuca</Cell><Cell>You can start dealing with the danger on the roads by talking to Sir Radzig after completing the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Baptism of Fire&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. Shortly after this point in the story, Sir Radzig will be found at the viewing point over Talmberg, and later at Pirkstein Castle in Rattay. If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc3Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. This assignment may be temporarily unavailable during the military operations towards the end of the main storyline, or may halt progress in the story for a while. </Cell><Cell>Ana görev &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Baptism of Fire&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; bitirdikten sonra, Sör Radzig ile konuşarak yollardaki tehlikelerle mücadele etmeye başlayabilirsin. Hikayenin bu kısmından sonra, Sör Radzig  ilk önce Talmberg'deki izleme noktasında, daha sonra ise Rattay'daki Pirkstein Kalesi'nde bulunabilir. Onu nerede bulacağınızı bilmiyorsan, &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc3Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; işaretine bak. Bu görev, ana hikayenin sonlarına doğru olan askeri operasyonlar sırasında geçici olarak deaktif olabilir, ya da bir süre hikayenin ilerlemesini durdurabilir.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc3_sch8_9v0p_e23_kzPo</Cell><Cell>Travelling the roads in the province is hazardous - merchants are afraid even to stick their noses out of the inns, visiting relatives in neighbouring villages is a life or death gamble and folk living in remote farmsteads sleep with axes under their pillows. Behind any oak or ash along the wayside, there may be a ruthless bandit lying in wait, or even a poor student, who has drunk away his last Groschen and entered the spirit of these lawless times. Either way, the victim is lucky to lose only his purse, and not his head. </Cell><Cell>Bölgeler arası seyahat etmek oldukça tehlikeli öyle ki -  satıcılar hanlardan dışarı çıkmak istemiyor, komşu köylerdeki akrabaları ziyarete gitmek tam bir ölüm kalım kumarı ve yerleşim yerine uzak çiftliklerde yaşayan insanlar yastıklarının altında baltalar ile uyuyorlar. Acımasız bir haydut ya da son groşenini içkiye vermiş bir ve kanun tanımayan bir öğrenci, yol kenarındaki bir ağacın veya çalılığın arkasına pusuya yatmış olabilir. Her halükarda, kurban kafası yerine sadece cüzdanını kaybederse şanslı sayılır.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc3_sch8_9v0p_e24_xgFu</Cell><Cell>You can see Sir Radzig and begin dealing with the dangers lurking on the provincial roads. He can usually be found at Pirkstein Castle in Rattay. If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc3Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. This assignment may be temporarily unavailable during the military operations towards the end of the main storyline, or may halt progress in the story for a while. </Cell><Cell>Sör Radzig ile buluşup bölgeler arası yollardaki tehlikelerle mücadele etmeye başlayabilirsin. Kendisi genellikle Rattay'daki Pirkstein Kalesi'nde olur. Onu nerede bulacağını bilmiyorsan &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc3Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; işaretine bak. Bu görev, ana hikayenin sonlarına doğru olan askeri operasyonlar sırasında geçici olarak deaktif olabilir, ya da bir süre hikayenin ilerlemesini durdurabilir.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc4_sch1_AMrB_e3098_CkTL</Cell><Cell>Talk to Johanka</Cell><Cell>Talk to Johanka</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc4_sch15_0k9l_e13_o1c5</Cell><Cell>Once she goes into Skalitz, Theresa can't continue to pursue side quests and won't be able to save the survivors outside.</Cell><Cell>Once she goes into Skalitz, Theresa can't continue to pursue side quests and won't be able to save the survivors outside.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch20_Bmon_e2_Zpwe</Cell><Cell>Foe</Cell><Cell>Düşman</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch20_Bmon_e3_4ZbU</Cell><Cell>Fight</Cell><Cell>Savaş</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch20_Bmon_e4_pPRz</Cell><Cell>Stop</Cell><Cell>Dur</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch20_Bmon_e6_FZId</Cell><Cell>Flee</Cell><Cell>Kaç</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch20_Bmon_e8_evade</Cell><Cell>Evade</Cell><Cell>Kaçın</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch3_6Ntp_e1050_ShB2</Cell><Cell>You blacked out and have no idea how you got here.</Cell><Cell>Bayıldın ve buraya nasıl geldiğini bilmiyorsun.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C__sch0_kfJy_e117_T7YN</Cell><Cell>There's no time. You're under attack!</Cell><Cell>Süre yok. Saldırı altındasın!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C__sch0_kfJy_e131_CFPj</Cell><Cell>You abandoned your lord and he died. For that you'll swing on the gallows.</Cell><Cell>Efendini yalnız bıraktın ve öldü. Bu yaptığının bedelini darağacında sallanarak ödeyeceksin.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch1_oPBP_e1311_7rP3</Cell><Cell>Pick roses</Cell><Cell>Gül topla</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch1_oPBP_e597_vKdO</Cell><Cell>Get into the bath dressed.</Cell><Cell>Kıyafetlerinle küvete gir.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch1_oPBP_e598_e1oH</Cell><Cell>Take off the clothes and get into the bath.</Cell><Cell>Kıyafetlerini çıkar ve küvete gir.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch2_dZo8_e1718_qbrs</Cell><Cell>A certain robber baron by the name of Wolflin of Kamberg has been pillaging farms in the fiefdom of Rattay with his band of renegades. The Lord of Rattay, Sir Hanush, takes a very dim view of his estates being ransacked, and so he's sent out a punitive expedition to deal with the outlaws. You are to take part.</Cell><Cell>Kambergli Wolflin adlı bir hırsız baron, hırsızlar çetesiyle Rattay etrafındaki çiftlikleri yağmalıyor. Rattay Lordu Sör Hanush, topraklarının yağmalanmasından hiç hoşlanmadı ve cezayı kesecek bir birlik gönderdi. Sen de bu ekibin bir parçasısın.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch2_dZo8_e1719_yQKd</Cell><Cell>Your corps is about to attack Wolflin's encampment. It will be a tough battle, because the enemy is expecting you and your forces are more or less matched. Arm yourself well and may God guide your hand!</Cell><Cell>Birliğin Wolflin'in kampına saldırmak üzere. Zor bir çarpışma olacak çünkü düşman sizi bekliyor ve asker sayılarınız aşağı yukarı aynı. İyi silahlan ve Tanrı sana yardımcı olsun.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e1_FNiR</Cell><Cell>There's never a dull moment with the bold Sir Hans Capon. Before he can proceed with his knightly duties, he wants me to help him with a certain delicate matter of great urgency. </Cell><Cell>Cesur Sör Hans Capon'la beraberken bir an bile sıkıcı geçmiyor. Kendi şövalye işlerine devam etmeden önce benden olfukçs önrmli, acil bir meselede yardım istedi.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e11_pHxc</Cell><Cell>The beginning of a new adventure with Sir Hans is active at the end of the Capon quest line, culminating in the &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Robber Baron&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; assigment, which can be started after the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Questions and Answers.&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; Capon, however, has no time for amorous adventures during the battles towards the end of the game, so you won't be able to accept the quest from him until the very end, when Sir Hans arrives at the camp by Neuhof. If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc2Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon.</Cell><Cell>Sör Hans ile yeni serüvenin başlangıcı, Capon görev sırasının sonunda doğru etkinleşir, &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Sorular ve Cevaplar&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; ana görevinden sonra başlanabilecek &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Hırsız Baron&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; görevi ile sonlanır. Lakin oyunun sonuna doğru Capon'un şehvetli maceralar içi vakti olmayacak, o yüzden görevi Sör Hans Neuhof'taki kampa gidene kadar ondan kabul edemeyeceksin. Eğer onu nerede bulabileceğinden emin değilsen, &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_quest_starter.dds' width='36' height='32'&amp;gt; simgesini ara.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e13_J5OK</Cell><Cell>The beginning of a new adventure with Sir Hans is now active. All you have to do is go and talk to him. Capon, however, has no time for amorous adventures during the battles towards the end of the game, so you won't be able to accept the quest from him until the very end, when Sir Hans goes to the camp at Neuhof. If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc2Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon.</Cell><Cell>Sör Hans ile yeni serüvenin başlangıcı artık etkin. Tek yapılması gereken gidip onunla konuşmak. Lakin oyunun sonuna doğru Capon'un şehvetli maceralar içi vakti olmayacak, o yüzden görevi Sör Hans Neuhof'taki kampa gidene kadar ondan kabul edemeyeceksin. Eğer onu nerede bulabileceğinden emin değilsen, &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_quest_starter.dds' width='36' height='32'&amp;gt; simgesini ara.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e2_Kw10</Cell><Cell>Knowing that Sir Hans has somewhat different priorities than the other local lords, it wouldn't be unreasonable to assume that a damsel is involved. After our last dramatic adventure at the bathhouse, I'm curious - and more than a little apprehensive - as to what his latest escapade will be all about.</Cell><Cell>Sör Hans'ın bölgedki diğer lortlardan daha farklı öncelikleri olduğunu hesaba katarsak olayın bir kadınla ilgili olduğunu düşünmek yanlış olmaz. Hamamda geçen heyecanlı maceramızdan sonra bu yeni maceranın neler getireceği konusunda meraklı ve biraz da endişeliyim.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e2_NFgO</Cell><Cell>Wicked tongues say the heir to the Town of Rattay, young Sir Hans Capon, is an incorrigible seducer and whore-monger. A more charitable view is that he's just looking for love. The kind you can't buy at the bathhouse...</Cell><Cell>Dedikoducuların dediklerine göre Rattay şehrinin varisi, genç Sör Hans Capon, iflah olmaz bir flörtöz ve kadın düşkünüymüş. Daha masum bir şekilde dile getirecek olursak o sadece aşkı arıyor. Hamamda satın alınamayacak cinsten bir aşkı.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e3_XzI6</Cell><Cell>You know the heir to the Town of Rattay, young Sir Hans Capon, well enough to realise that there's more than a little truth to the rumours that he's an incorrigible seducer and whore-monger. But then again, maybe he's just looking for love. The kind you can't buy at the bathhouse...</Cell><Cell>Rattay şehrinin varisi genç Sör Hans Capon'u hakkındaki onun iflah olmaz bir flörtöz ve kadın düşkünü olduğu dedikodularının doğruluk payı olduğunu bilecek kadar iyi tanıyorsun. Tabi belki de sadece aşkı arayan biridir. Hamamda bulunamayacak bir aşk.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e4_iPlE</Cell><Cell>You have yet to make the acquaintance of the bold Sir Hans Capon, but once you do, be prepared to get drawn into his amorous adventures. You, a common blacksmith's son, will become His Lordship's herald, his messenger of love!</Cell><Cell>Henüz cesur Sör Hans Capon'la tanışmadın ama tanıştıktan sonra onun şehvet dolu maceralarının bir parçası olmaya hazır ol. Sen, sıradan bir demirci çocuğu, Lort hazretlerinin yeni teşrifatçısı, onun aşkının habercisi olacaksın!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e6_YhfZ</Cell><Cell>You have a feeling that if you knew him better, you are very likely to get drawn into his amorous adventures. His Lordship's herald, his messenger of love - it has a ring to it!</Cell><Cell>İçinden bir his onu daha iyi tanısaydın, onun bu şehvet dolu maceralarının bir parçası olacağını söylüyor. Lort hazretlerinin teşrifatçısı, onun aşk habercisi. Kulağa hoş geliyor!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e9_SGAF</Cell><Cell>Sir Hans Capon, the rightful heir to the Town of Rattay, dedicates most of his time to educating himself in matters knightly. He excels at hunting, combat and horseriding... or so he believes. He hasn't mastered the nobel game of chess, or even the more common game of dice, and as for poetry recitation, the time has come for him to work on that, if he's to win the heart of the maiden of his dreams.</Cell><Cell>Rattay şehrinin varisi Sör Hans Capon, vaktinin çoğunu kendisini şövalyelere yakışır meselelerde eğitmeye harcar. Avcılıkta, ikili mücadelede ve ata binmede ustadır… En azından kendisi öyle olduğuna inanıyor. Soylu oyun satranç üzerine ya da daha ayak takımı oyunu zar üzerine uzmanlaşmamıştır, konu şiir yazmaya gelince, eğer hayallerindeki genç kızın kalbini çalacaksa, işte bu konuda uzmanlaşmasının vakti geldi. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch19_T9qy_e10_XLxy</Cell><Cell>Begin combat (easy foe)</Cell><Cell>Begin combat (easy foe)</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch19_T9qy_e11_EBhq</Cell><Cell>Begin combat (intermediate foe)</Cell><Cell>Begin combat (intermediate foe)</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch19_T9qy_e12_FPK6</Cell><Cell>Begin combat (hard foe)</Cell><Cell>Begin combat (hard foe)</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch19_T9qy_e13_h6fh</Cell><Cell>Begin combat with two foes</Cell><Cell>Begin combat with two foes</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch19_T9qy_e14_Bvcn</Cell><Cell>Begin battle (end of tutorial)</Cell><Cell>Begin battle (end of tutorial)</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e23_l8le</Cell><Cell>Black clouds of strife are gathering, the thundering drums of war rumble across the land and the whole  kingdom awaits the next lightning bolt with bated breath. Not so the undaunted Sir Hanush, who decided to bolster morale with a regular tourney to keep his subjects fighting fit and distract them from the pervasive gloom. </Cell><Cell>Savaşın kara bulutları gökyüzünün enginlerinde toplanırken, savaş davullarının gürleyişi diyarı sarsıyor ve herkes sabırsızlıkla bir sonraki yıldırımı bekliyordu. Pek korkusuz Sör Hanush, askerlerini savaş için zinde tutmak ve tüm diyarı pençesine alan kasvetten uzaklaştırmak için düzenli turnuvalar ile onların morallerini yüksek tutma kararı almıştı. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e24_Edki</Cell><Cell>The tourney takes place every few days by the Upper Castle in Rattay. All types of melee weapons are permitted, and the contest is open to combatants from all walks of life, even a lowborn, uneducated misfit like you. Just go and ask Sir Hans Capon about it and he'll tell you all you need to know.</Cell><Cell>Turnuva her birkaç günde bir Rattay'de Yukarı Kale'de düzenlenir. Tüm silah çeşitleri turnuva içinde kabul edilmektedir ve turnuva; senin gibi alt tabakadan ve eğitimsizin teki bile olsa hayatın her kesiminden katılımcılara açıktır. Git ve Sör Hans Capon ile bu konu hakkında konuş, o da sana bilmen gereken her şeyi anlatacaktır. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e26_cIeS</Cell><Cell>Black clouds of strife are gathering, the thundering drums of war rumble across the land and the whole  kingdom awaits the next lightning bolt with bated breath. Not so the undaunted Sir Hanush, who decided to bolster morale with a regular tourney to keep his subjects fighting fit and distract them from the pervasive gloom. </Cell><Cell>Savaşın kara bulutları gökyüzünün enginlerinde toplanırken, savaş davullarının gürleyişi diyarı sarsıyor ve herkes sabırsızlıkla bir sonraki yıldırımı bekliyordu. Pek korkusuz Sör Hanush, askerlerini savaş için zinde tutmak ve tüm diyarı pençesine alan kasvetten uzaklaştırmak için düzenli turnuvalar ile onların morallerini yüksek tutma kararı almıştı. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e27_dQji</Cell><Cell>The tourney takes place every few days by the Upper Castle in Rattay. All types of melee weapons are permitted, and the contest is open to combatants from all walks of life, even a lowborn, uneducated misfit like you. Young Sir Hans Capon will tell you all you need to know about it. Once you've become better acquainted with him, that is. </Cell><Cell>Turnuva her birkaç günde bir Rattay'de Yukarı Kale'de düzenlenir. Tüm silah çeşitleri turnuva içinde kabul edilmektedir ve turnuva; senin gibi alt tabakadan ve eğitimsizin teki bile olsa hayatın her kesiminden katılımcılara açıktır. Genç Sör Hans Capon, bilmen gereken her şeyi sana anlatacaktır. Tabii bunun için onu biraz daha yakından tanıman gerekiyor. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e30_5QY2</Cell><Cell>The tournament convened by Sir Hanush takes place once every seven days at Rattay Upper Castle. The aim of the tourney is to test the skill of combatants will all kinds of weapons. It's intended for commoners, so you can enrol too. </Cell><Cell>Rattay Yukarı Kale'de her yedi günde bir, Sör Hanush tarafınca turnuva düzenlenir. Turnuvanın amacı mücadelecilerin her çeşit silahla becerilerini ölçmektir. Turnuva halk tabakasından olanlar için düzenlenir, sen de katılabilirsin.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e32_m7B8</Cell><Cell>After completing the side quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Next to Godliness&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; with Sir Hans, you can accept a new quest from him, which will launch an instance of the regular tournament. If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlcTournamentOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. If you've already progressed in the storyline as far as &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Epilogue&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;, you won't be able to accept the quest from Capon and the Tournament will launch on its own. the tournament will not take place while Sir Hanush is at war. </Cell><Cell>&amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Temizlik İmandan Gelir&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; yan görevini Sör Hans ile tamamladıktan sonra, ondan yeni görevler talep edebilirsin, böylece düzenli turnuvalar başlatılmış olur. Eğer Sör Hans'ı nerede bulabileceğinden emin değilsen, &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlcTournamentOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt simgesini ara. Eğer hikâye gidişatını &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Kapanış&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;'a kadar tamamladıysan, Capon'dan görev alamayacaksın, turnuva kendi kendine başlayacaktır. Sör Hanush savaştayken turnuva düzenlenmez.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e34_2Ipt</Cell><Cell>You can go and see Sir Hans and accept from him a new quest, which will launch a regular tournament. If you're not sure where to find Sir Hans, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlcTournamentOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. If you've already progressed in the storyline as far as &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Epilogue&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;, you won't be able to accept the quest from Capon and the tournament will launch on its own. The tournament will not take place while Sir Hanush is at war. </Cell><Cell>Gidip Sör Hans'ı görebilir ve ondan yeni bir görev kabul edebilirsin, böylece düzenli turnuvalar başlayacaktır. Eğer Sör Hans'ı nerede bulabileceğinden emin değilsen, &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlcTournamentOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; simgesini ara. Eğer hikâye gidişatını &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Kapanış&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;'a kadar tamamladıysan, Capon'dan görev alamayacaksın, turnuva kendi kendine başlayacaktır. Sör Hanush savaştayken turnuva düzenlenmez.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e36_F5Dq</Cell><Cell>After launching the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; in Rattay, a tournament will be automatically launched every week at Rattay Upper Castle. The tournament will not take place, however, while Sir Hanush is at war. </Cell><Cell>Rattay'da &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Uyanış&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; adlı ana görevi başlattıktan sonra, Rattay Yukarı Kale'de her hafta turnuva düzenlenir. Ancak Sör Hanush savaştayken turnuva yapılmaz.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap27_PxIe_sch0_c5YT_e131_Qgwo</Cell><Cell>Quest started</Cell><Cell>Görev başladı</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap27_PxIe_sch0_c5YT_e132_70UZ</Cell><Cell>Blessing of overseer</Cell><Cell>Ustabaşının duası.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap27_PxIe_sch0_c5YT_e132_gMEy</Cell><Cell>Chasing Zmola</Cell><Cell>Zmola'yı kovalamak</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap27_PxIe_sch0_c5YT_e132_H3Q2</Cell><Cell>Disappearance of Leshek</Cell><Cell>Leshek'in kayboluşu</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap32_sch1_Yhte_e2_eyDY</Cell><Cell>Wayfarer</Cell><Cell>Yaya</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap32_sch1_Yhte_e4_dQKb</Cell><Cell>Examine</Cell><Cell>İncele</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap32_sch1_Yhte_e5_yZbc</Cell><Cell>Ignore</Cell><Cell>Görmezden gel</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap32_sch1_Yhte_e7_obSX</Cell><Cell>Stop  </Cell><Cell>Dur</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap32_sch1_Yhte_e8_5efG</Cell><Cell>Flee</Cell><Cell>Kaç</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e52_pzSy</Cell><Cell>To your surprise, you've found there are some interesting papers amongst your things. Most likely they were concealed in the saddlebag of the horse you escaped from Skalitz on. It seems the men of the Talmberg garrison assumed they were yours and put them in your trunk. But how would a common blacksmith's son come by such documents? After all, you can't even read! The mysterious documents have an ancient seal that testifies to the noble and ancient origin of their author. </Cell><Cell>Hayrettir ki eşyalarının arasında birkaç ilginç kâğıt buldun. Büyük ihtimalle Skalitz'ten kaçtığın atın eyer çantasına gizlenmişler. Görünüşe göre Talmberg garnizonundaki askerler kâğıtların senin olduğunu düşünüp yanına koymuşlar. Ama basit bir demircinin oğlu böyle belgeleri ne yapacak ki? Daha okuyamıyorsun bile! Gizemli belgelerin üzerinde yazarın soyluluğunu ve geçmişini gösteren kadim bir mühür var.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e53_nsaj</Cell><Cell>You're not able to make any sense out of their content, but, luckily for you, you're not the first one to examine them. And whoever it was that read them, that learned person created a number of simple sketches based on their content, which look like descriptions of places where rare items of clothing and armour are hidden! You've put the papers safely away in your trunk, where they're waiting until you have time to study them more closely.</Cell><Cell>Ne yazdığını anlayamıyorsun ancak şansına onları inceleyen ilk kişi sen değilsin. Her kim okuduysa üstünde yazanlara göre birtakım basit çizim yapmış; nadir kıyafetlerin ve zırhların saklandığı yerlerin tasvirine benziyor! Kâğıtları sakince sandığına kaldırdın, daha yakından inceleyene kadar orada bekleyecekler.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e56_v6wf</Cell><Cell>A legend is circulating in the province about stashes containing magnificent Warhorse armour. Many people have searched for it, but in vain. With a little effort and the grace of God, perhaps you can succeed in finding the armour and donning it to assist you in fighting the good fight!</Cell><Cell>Muazzam Savaşatı zırhını içeren zulaların vilayetteki varlığıyla ilgili efsaneler dolanıyor. Birçok insan onu araştırdı ancak nafile. Birazcık uğraşla ve Tanrı'nın inayetiyle, belki seni kuşatacak ve iyi bir mücadele çıkaramana yardım edecek zırhı bulabilirsin.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e58_tSzl</Cell><Cell>The first part of the Warhorse armour and five treasure maps will appear in your universal trunk after launching the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; in Rattay Mill. You can access your trunk from any home or lodgings you have in the world.</Cell><Cell>Savaşatı zırhının ilk parçası ve beş tane hazine haritası, &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Uyanış&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; ana görevinden sonra Rattay Değirmeni'ndeki evrensel sandığında çıkar. Sandığına, dünyadaki herhangi konaklama yerlerinden ve evlerinden erişebilirsin.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e60_b6T9</Cell><Cell>The first part of the Warhorse armour and five more treasure maps are stored in your universal trunk in Rattay Mill. You can access your trunk from any home or lodgings you have in the world.</Cell><Cell>Savaşatı zırhının ilk parçası ve beş tane hazine haritası Rattay Değirmeni'ndeki evrensel sandığında bulunuyor. Sandığına, dünyadaki herhangi konaklama yerlerinden ve evlerinden erişebilirsin.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e29_B18G</Cell><Cell>Although you hardly ventured beyond Skalitz your whole life, now and again you heard tidings from travelling merchants and wayfarers about goings on in the outside world - the big harvest festival in Merhojed, the rebuilding of Sasau Monastery and stories about an abandoned village in the woods near Talmberg. </Cell><Cell>Hayatın boyunca Skalitz'in dışında pek çıkmamış olsan da arada sırada gezginlerden ve yolculardan dış dünyayla ilgili bilgiler ediniyordun; Merhojed'deki büyük hasat festivali, Sasau Manastırı'nın restorasyonu ve Talmberg'in yanındaki ormanda bulunan terk edilmiş bir köy ile ilgili hikâyeler.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e30_zOG0</Cell><Cell>That village is called Pribyslavitz, and for years it has lain in ruins. You've always been curious about it - where exactly it is, what mysteries it conceals and why no one ever went back there to live. You're determined to go there and explore the village, just as soon as you and the local lords have dealt with the bandits.</Cell><Cell>Bu köyün adı Pribyslavitz ve yıllardır da yıkılmış vaziyette. Bu konuyu hep merak etmişsindir; tam olarak nerede, ne gibi gizemler barındırıyor ve neden kimse oraya yaşamaya gitmemiş. Sen ve bölge lortların haydutlarla ilgilendikten sonra oraya gidip köyü keşfetmeye karar verdin.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e32_eqgM</Cell><Cell>After you and your comrades-in-arms drove the bandits out of Pribyslavitz, the village was once again left to be slowly swallowed up by the woods. A shame - before being plundered by a renegade lord, it was no doubt a sprawling, bustling hamlet, judging by the size of the ruined church there, which is all that's left as a reminder of its former prosperity.</Cell><Cell>Sen ve silah arkadaşların haydutları Pribyslavitz'ten attıktan sonra köy tekrardan ormanın kucağında yavaş yavaş çürümeye bırakıldı. Ne kadar yazık; hain bir lort tarafından yağmalanmadan önce kalıntıları kalmış kiliseye bakacak olursak şüphesiz ki büyüyen, canlı bir köymüş, şimdi ise eski hâlinden geriye sadece bir anı kalmış.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e33_mdnB</Cell><Cell>You always wondered why the folk never went back to live there, so you were pleasantly surprised to learn that Sir Divish has plans for his former hamlet. You don't know exactly what he has in mind, but you'll be glad to have a hand in it. You're sure to find out in Talmberg what needs to be done.</Cell><Cell>İnsanların neden orada yaşamak için tekrar gitmediklerini hep merak etmişsindir, bu yüzden Sör Divish'in eski köyü hakkındaki planlarını öğrenince tatlı bir şaşkınlığa uğradın. Aklında ne olduğunu tam olarak bilmiyorsun, ancak yardım ettiğin için mutlusun. Ne yapılması gerektiğini Talmberg'de öğreneceğine eminsin.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e41_Z7m2</Cell><Cell>Pribyslavitz, a sprawling, long-abandoned village, is now swallowed up by the woods. You always wondered what secrets it concealed and why the villagers never returned there, and so you were pleasantly surprised when Sir Divish told you he had plans for the old settlement. </Cell><Cell>Uzun zaman önce terk edilmiş genişçe bir köy olan Pribyslavitz şimdilerde orman tarafından yutulmuş halde. Hep ne gibi sırlar barındırdığını ve oraya köylülerin neden dönmediğini merak etmişsindir. Sör Divish bu eski yerleşke hakkındaki planlarını sana söylediğinde mutlu bir sürpriz yaşadın.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e43_Sx5N</Cell><Cell>Sir Divish enlists your help in rebuilding Pribyslavitz after the bandits have been driven out of the hamlet in the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Baptism of Fire.&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc1Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. However, you will temporarily not be able to launch or continue playing the DLC during any battle quests.</Cell><Cell>&amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Ateşle İmtihan&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; adlı ana görevle birlikte köydeki eşkıyalar kovulduktan sonra Sör Divish, Pribyslavitz'i yeniden inşa etmek için yardımını kabul eder. Eğer onu nerede bulacağını bilmiyorsan, &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc1Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; simgesini bul. Aklında olsun, mücadele sırasında geçici olarak inşaayı durdurmak ya da tamamlamak mümkün değildir. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e45_P5pu</Cell><Cell>Go and see Sir Divish, who wants you to help rebuild Pribyslavitz.  If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc1Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. Bear in mind, though, that it will not be possible to temporarily resume or complete the rebuilding during any battles. </Cell><Cell>Pribyslavitz'i tamir etmeye yardım etmeni isteyen Sör Divish'i görmeye git. Eğer onu nerede bulacağını bilmiyorsan, &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc1Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; simgesini bul. Aklında olsun, mücadele sırasında geçici olarak inşaayı durdurmak ya da tamamlamak mümkün değildir. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch5_mZpP_e507_HUZ7</Cell><Cell>A few days later.</Cell><Cell>Birkaç gün sonra.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e11_xZNi</Cell><Cell>You can get a dog from Theresa at Rattay Mill, but only after launching the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;.</Cell><Cell>You can get a dog from Theresa at Rattay Mill, but only after launching the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e13_pa33</Cell><Cell>Theresa's story is now active. You can launch the quest line by talking to Theresa. You'll be led to her by &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4TheresaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell><Cell>Theresa's story is now active. You can launch the quest line by talking to Theresa. You'll be led to her by &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4TheresaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e17_jskP</Cell><Cell>Theresa is now looking after a dog at Rattay Mill. She's hoping you take it over, because her uncle, Miller Peshek, doesn't like the animal. Go and see Theresa and offer to help.</Cell><Cell>Theresa is now looking after a dog at Rattay Mill. She's hoping you take it over, because her uncle, Miller Peshek, doesn't like the animal. Go and see Theresa and offer to help.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e21_BK5Z</Cell><Cell>A difficult fate awaits Johanka. To find out more, go and visit her at the monastery infirmary and look for &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4JohankaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;</Cell><Cell>A difficult fate awaits Johanka. To find out more, go and visit her at the monastery infirmary and look for &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4JohankaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e3_k92t</Cell><Cell>Armed with fortitude and dignity, she faces the coming days with a smile on her lips. And since God moves in mysterious ways, none of us can know the lot we shall have to bear. But it is often those of whom we least expect it who encounter an extraordinary destiny...</Cell><Cell>Armed with fortitude and dignity, she faces the coming days with a smile on her lips. And since God moves in mysterious ways, none of us can know the lot we shall have to bear. But it is often those of whom we least expect it who encounter an extraordinary destiny...</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e5_oXts</Cell><Cell>You're the son of a blacksmith, whose life centred around the forge, not farming and livestock. It's not as if you ever missed cattle or pigs, but to have a dog of your own? Now that would be nice...</Cell><Cell>You're the son of a blacksmith, whose life centred around the forge, not farming and livestock. It's not as if you ever missed cattle or pigs, but to have a dog of your own? Now that would be nice...</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e7_tMbu</Cell><Cell>Theresa's story will be available to you once you launch the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. Then all you have to do is talk to Theresa in Rattay Mill. You'll be led to her by &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4TheresaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell><Cell>Theresa's story will be available to you once you launch the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. Then all you have to do is talk to Theresa in Rattay Mill. You'll be led to her by &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4TheresaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e9_AUe9</Cell><Cell>A difficult fate awaits Johanka. To find out more about it, you must have completed the side quests &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Pestilence&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;In God's Hands&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;, whether successfully or not. You will get to &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Pestilence&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; from the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Questions and Answers&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;In God's Hands&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; is assigned to you by Johanka, who is to be found at Sasau Monastery. Once you've completed those quests, all you have to do is visit Johanka again, where you will be guided by &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4JohankaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell><Cell>A difficult fate awaits Johanka. To find out more about it, you must have completed the side quests &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Pestilence&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;In God's Hands&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;, whether successfully or not. You will get to &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Pestilence&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; from the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Questions and Answers&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;In God's Hands&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; is assigned to you by Johanka, who is to be found at Sasau Monastery. Once you've completed those quests, all you have to do is visit Johanka again, where you will be guided by &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4JohankaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch35_xmhH_e337_KWau</Cell><Cell>Preacher</Cell><Cell>Vaiz</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e13_bdlz</Cell><Cell>Hold-up</Cell><Cell>Soygun</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e14_Ii0w</Cell><Cell>Don't interfere in it</Cell><Cell>Müdahale etme</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e18_AlMX</Cell><Cell>Fight</Cell><Cell>Dövüş</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e19_lmga</Cell><Cell>Watch the battle</Cell><Cell>Savaşı izle</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e19_velx</Cell><Cell>Flee</Cell><Cell>Kaç</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e23_Onaq</Cell><Cell>Untie</Cell><Cell>Çöz</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e497_Jylz</Cell><Cell>Carcass on the Road</Cell><Cell>Yolda Ceset Var</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e498_udhL</Cell><Cell>Stop</Cell><Cell>Dur</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e499_Gkvg</Cell><Cell>Ride around and ignore it</Cell><Cell>Etrafından dolan ve görmezden gel</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e500_6K58</Cell><Cell>Go around and ignore it</Cell><Cell>Etrafından dolan ve görmezden gel</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e503_wcog</Cell><Cell>Have a chat</Cell><Cell>Konuş</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e504_4I17</Cell><Cell>Flee</Cell><Cell>Kaç</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e514_FS5n</Cell><Cell>Look at the weapon</Cell><Cell>Silaha bak</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch45_nmtr_e95_BhsL</Cell><Cell>Give the convict a drink.</Cell><Cell>Hükümlüye içecek ver.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch47_94Dl_e1_W2wk</Cell><Cell>Chase</Cell><Cell>Kovalama</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e1_O1wc</Cell><Cell>Attack on the road</Cell><Cell>Yolda Saldırı Var</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e16_ewho</Cell><Cell>Scout</Cell><Cell>Keşfe çık</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e17_PQwb</Cell><Cell>Halt</Cell><Cell>Durdur</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e18_2dRv</Cell><Cell>Run away</Cell><Cell>Kaç</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e19_RGfd</Cell><Cell>Avoid</Cell><Cell>Uzak dur</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch15_T7No_e6_QlXw</Cell><Cell>Too many of your men have died.</Cell><Cell>Çok fazla adamın öldü!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch2_iRf2_e11_6IvY</Cell><Cell>The early 15th century was a time of turmoil in the Holy Roman Empire, which had flourished under the late Emperor Charles IV, but now, with his son Wenceslas “the Idle“ on the Bohemian throne, was falling into disarray.

</Cell><Cell>15. yüzyılın başı, Kutsal Roma İmparatorluğu için tam bir karmaşaydı. İmparator IV. Charles'ın yönetiminde büyümüş olan imparatorluk, veliaht "Durgun" Wenceslas Bohemya tahtına geçince karmaşaya doğru sürüklenmekteydi.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch2_iRf2_e12_U8N0</Cell><Cell>The King’s inactivity angered many of the nobility, as well as his half-brother, King Sigismund of Hungary, who decided to take drastic steps to restore order to the Empire…
</Cell><Cell>Kral'ın durgunluğu birçok soylunun yanında üvey kardeşi Macaristan Kralı Sigismund'u da kızdırmıştır ve Sigismund bu yüzden İmparatorluğa düzeni geri getirmek için önemli adımlar atmaya karar vermiştir…</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch2_iRf2_e12_vkUl</Cell><Cell>Silver Skalitz, 1403</Cell><Cell>Gümüş Skalitz, 1403</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch2_iRf2_e990_QBhT</Cell><Cell>Throw manure.</Cell><Cell>Gübre fırlat.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch22_LAqJ_e810_xbED</Cell><Cell>Skip mass</Cell><Cell>Ayine katılma</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch22_LAqJ_e815_OUNX</Cell><Cell>Eat</Cell><Cell>Yemek ye</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch25_kJcP_e58_PAkf</Cell><Cell>Raise the portcullis</Cell><Cell>Kale kapısını aç</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch25_kJcP_e9_mUC2</Cell><Cell>Before the return to Talmberg</Cell><Cell>Talmberg'e dönüşten önce.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch28_w7oB_e271_IWz9</Cell><Cell>You did not arrive at the battleground.</Cell><Cell>Savaş alanına ulaşamadın.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch28_w7oB_e273_wPqw</Cell><Cell>You fled the battlefield.</Cell><Cell>Savaş alanından kaçtın.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch7_9t19_e58_Suu4</Cell><Cell>In the castle.</Cell><Cell>Kalede.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch7_9t19_e8_Zrcd</Cell><Cell>Run!</Cell><Cell>Koş!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch7_nFPk_e311_GKf6</Cell><Cell>Zbyshek killed you while you were unconscious.</Cell><Cell>Sen baygınken Zbyshek seni öldürdü.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch8_Votg_e104_iWG2</Cell><Cell>A FEW DELIRIOUS DAYS LATER…</Cell><Cell>BİRKAÇ GÜN SONRA</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch8_Votg_e186_2516</Cell><Cell>AND EVEN LATER…</Cell><Cell>DAHA DA SONRA</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch9_FEsU_e1491_2eLv</Cell><Cell>Inspect</Cell><Cell>Denetle</Cell></Row>
</Table>