<Table>
<Row><Cell>game_over_basicTraining</Cell><Cell>You've lost the trust of Sir Radzig.</Cell><Cell>Has perdido la confianza de sir Radzig.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_conquest_fled</Cell><Cell>Without your help, Istvan won the Battle of Talmberg.</Cell><Cell>Istvan ganó la batalla de Talmberk sin recibir vuestra ayuda.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_conquest_follow_capon</Cell><Cell>Without getting help, your father died.</Cell><Cell>Vuestro padre murió sin recibir ayuda.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_counteroffensive_reinforcements</Cell><Cell>You didn't get the reinforcements to Vranik from Talmberg.</Cell><Cell>No has llevado los refuerzos de Talmberk hasta Vraník.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_bleeding</Cell><Cell>You have bled to death.</Cell><Cell>Te has desangrado hasta morir.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_collision</Cell><Cell>You have died.</Cell><Cell>Has muerto.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_fall</Cell><Cell>You have fallen to your death.</Cell><Cell>Te has matado en una caída.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_poison</Cell><Cell>You have been poisoned.</Cell><Cell>Has sido envenenado.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_scripted_hit</Cell><Cell>You were murdered under unforseen circumstances.</Cell><Cell>Te han asesinado en circunstancias inesperadas.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_self_harm</Cell><Cell>You have died by your own hand.</Cell><Cell>Has muerto por tu propia mano.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_starving</Cell><Cell>You have starved to death. </Cell><Cell>Te has muerto de hambre.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_in_combat</Cell><Cell>You have died in combat.</Cell><Cell>Has muerto en combate.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_in_jail</Cell><Cell>You have died in jail.</Cell><Cell>Has muerto en la cárcel.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_unknown</Cell><Cell>You have died.</Cell><Cell>Has muerto.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_E3_lost</Cell><Cell>You have lost the battle.</Cell><Cell>Has perdido la batalla.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_E3_win</Cell><Cell>You are victorious!</Cell><Cell>¡La victoria es tuya!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_escape_skalitz</Cell><Cell>You've been hit by a stray Cuman arrow.</Cell><Cell>Te ha dado una flecha cumana perdida.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_escape_talmberk</Cell><Cell>Robard is really angry at you right now.</Cell><Cell>Ahora mismo Robard está muy enfadado.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_finished</Cell><Cell>Game finished</Cell><Cell>Fin de la partida</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_killed_by_zmola</Cell><Cell>Zmola killed you while you were unconscious.</Cell><Cell>Zmola te ha matado mientras estabas inconsciente.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_killed_while_unconscious</Cell><Cell>You were killed while unconscious.</Cell><Cell>Te han matado mientras estabas inconsciente.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_lostBattle</Cell><Cell>You lost the battle.</Cell><Cell>Has perdido la batalla.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_night_rescue_crime</Cell><Cell>You committed treachery!</Cell><Cell>¡Has cometido traición!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_night_rescue_ran_away</Cell><Cell>Young Lord Capon died while attempting to rescue the hostages.</Cell><Cell>El joven lord Capon ha muerto mientras intentaba rescatar a los rehenes.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_nights_watch</Cell><Cell>You've been kicked out of the Bailiff's service for incompetence.</Cell><Cell>Te han echado del servicio del merino por incompetente.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_ptacek_bled</Cell><Cell>Capon lost 5 pints of blood. His goose is cooked.</Cell><Cell>Capon ha perdido 5 pintas de sangre. No hay nada que hacer.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_revelation_killing_inquisitor_text</Cell><Cell>Murdering a servant of God is a most heinous crime! You tried to flee, but they soon caught up with you. Sir Radzig turned his back on you and you were hanged for your crime. Johanka was convicted of heresy and died as a result of her punishment.</Cell><Cell>¡Asesinar a un siervo de Dios es un delito repulsivo! Intentaste huir, pero pronto te dieron caza. Sir Radzig te dio la espalda y te ahorcaron por tus crímenes. Johanka fue condenada por herejía y murió a causa de su castigo.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_revelation_killing_inquisitor_undercover_seen_text</Cell><Cell>You were seen killing the Inquisitor and the law soon caught up with you. Sir Radzig turned his back on you and you were hanged for your crime.</Cell><Cell>Te vieron asesinando al inquisidor y el brazo de la ley no tardó en darte caza. Sir Radzig te dio la espalda y te ahorcaron por tus crímenes.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_revelation_speking_heresy_text</Cell><Cell>You died after your tongue was cut out for heretical speeches. Johanka was also convicted of heresy and suffered the same fate.</Cell><Cell>Te cortaron la lengua por tus discursos heréticos y las heridas te provocaron la muerte. Johanka también fue condenada por herejía y sufrió el mismo destino.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_run</Cell><Cell>A village lad like you has no chance of defeating the fearsome Cumans. Better to run and save your skin.</Cell><Cell>Un muchacho aldeano como tú no tiene ninguna posibilidad de derrotar a los temibles cumanos. Más vale que corras para salvar el pellejo.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_simek_text</Cell><Cell>Samuel died.</Cell><Cell>Samuel ha muerto.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_tereza_escape</Cell><Cell>You were hit by a stray Cuman arrow and died while trying to flee.</Cell><Cell>Te ha dado una flecha cumana perdida y has muerto cuando intentabas huir.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_tereza_prison</Cell><Cell>You've been executed for your grave crimes. May God have mercy on your sinful soul.</Cell><Cell>Te han ejecutado por tus graves delitos. Que el Señor tenga piedad de tu alma pecaminosa.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_test</Cell><Cell>TEST</Cell><Cell>PRUEBA</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_thank_you</Cell><Cell>Thank you for playing!</Cell><Cell>¡Gracias por jugar!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc2_sch2_GhfW_e1050_G8Y7</Cell><Cell>Replace</Cell><Cell>Sustituir</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc2_sch2_GhfW_e1051_XHhc</Cell><Cell>Bury</Cell><Cell>Enterrar</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc2_sch2_GhfW_e1210_8zxc</Cell><Cell>Colour the water</Cell><Cell>Teñir el agua</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc2_sch2_GhfW_e1508_DCgh</Cell><Cell>Throw</Cell><Cell>Arrojar</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc3_sch8_9v0p_e20_O9rb</Cell><Cell>Travelling the roads in the province is hazardous - merchants are afraid even to stick their noses out of the inns, visiting relatives in neighbouring villages is a life or death gamble and folk living in remote farmsteads sleep with axes under their pillows. Behind any oak or ash along the wayside, there may be a ruthless bandit lying in wait, or even a poor student, who has drunk away his last Groschen and entered the spirit of these lawless times. Either way, the victim is lucky to lose only his purse, and not his head. </Cell><Cell>Viajar por los caminos de la provincia es peligroso. Los comerciantes temen hasta entrar en las posadas, visitar a familiares en aldeas vecinas es jugarse la vida y la gente que vive en granjas remotas duerme con el hacha debajo de la almohada. Detrás de cualquier roble o fresno del camino puede haber un bandido despiadado al acecho, o incluso un estudiante pobre, que se ha bebido hasta su último groschen y se ha dejado arrastrar por espíritu ingobernable de estos tiempos. Sea como sea, para la víctima es una suerte perder solo el bolso y no la cabeza. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc3_sch8_9v0p_e21_Nuca</Cell><Cell>You can start dealing with the danger on the roads by talking to Sir Radzig after completing the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Baptism of Fire&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. Shortly after this point in the story, Sir Radzig will be found at the viewing point over Talmberg, and later at Pirkstein Castle in Rattay. If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc3Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. This assignment may be temporarily unavailable during the military operations towards the end of the main storyline, or may halt progress in the story for a while. </Cell><Cell>Puedes empezar a lidiar con los peligros de los caminos si hablas con sir Radzig después de completar la misión principal &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Bautismo de fuego&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. Poco después de este punto de la historia, sir Radzig se encontrará en el mirador sobre Talmberk, y después en el castillo de Pirkštejn, en Rataje. Si no sabes dónde encontrarlo, busca el icono &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc3Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;. Esta misión puede no estar disponible temporalmente durante las operaciones militares hacia el final de la historia principal o puede detener el progreso de la historia durante un tiempo. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc3_sch8_9v0p_e23_kzPo</Cell><Cell>Travelling the roads in the province is hazardous - merchants are afraid even to stick their noses out of the inns, visiting relatives in neighbouring villages is a life or death gamble and folk living in remote farmsteads sleep with axes under their pillows. Behind any oak or ash along the wayside, there may be a ruthless bandit lying in wait, or even a poor student, who has drunk away his last Groschen and entered the spirit of these lawless times. Either way, the victim is lucky to lose only his purse, and not his head. </Cell><Cell>Viajar por los caminos de la provincia es peligroso. Los comerciantes temen hasta entrar en las posadas, visitar a familiares en aldeas vecinas es jugarse la vida y la gente que vive en granjas remotas duerme con el hacha debajo de la almohada. Detrás de cualquier roble o fresno del camino puede haber un bandido despiadado al acecho, o incluso un estudiante pobre, que se ha bebido hasta su último groschen y se ha dejado arrastrar por espíritu ingobernable de estos tiempos. Sea como sea, para la víctima es una suerte perder solo el bolso y no la cabeza. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc3_sch8_9v0p_e24_xgFu</Cell><Cell>You can see Sir Radzig and begin dealing with the dangers lurking on the provincial roads. He can usually be found at Pirkstein Castle in Rattay. If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc3Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. This assignment may be temporarily unavailable during the military operations towards the end of the main storyline, or may halt progress in the story for a while. </Cell><Cell>Puedes ver a sir Radzig y empezar a lidiar con los peligros que acechan en los caminos de la provincia. Normalmente se encuentra en el castillo de Pirkštejn, en Rataje. Si no sabes dónde encontrarlo, busca el icono &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc3Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;. Esta misión puede no estar disponible temporalmente durante las operaciones militares hacia el final de la historia principal o puede detener el progreso de la historia durante un tiempo. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc4_sch1_AMrB_e3098_CkTL</Cell><Cell>Talk to Johanka</Cell><Cell>Hablar con Johanka</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc4_sch15_0k9l_e13_o1c5</Cell><Cell>Once she goes into Skalitz, Theresa can't continue to pursue side quests and won't be able to save the survivors outside.</Cell><Cell>Una vez que llegue a Skalice, Theresa no podrá intentar misiones secundarias ni salvar a los supervivientes del exterior.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch20_Bmon_e2_Zpwe</Cell><Cell>Foe</Cell><Cell>Enemigo</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch20_Bmon_e3_4ZbU</Cell><Cell>Fight</Cell><Cell>Luchar</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch20_Bmon_e4_pPRz</Cell><Cell>Stop</Cell><Cell>Parar</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch20_Bmon_e6_FZId</Cell><Cell>Flee</Cell><Cell>Huir</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch20_Bmon_e8_evade</Cell><Cell>Evade</Cell><Cell>Esquivar</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch3_6Ntp_e1050_ShB2</Cell><Cell>You blacked out and have no idea how you got here.</Cell><Cell>Al haber perdido el sentido, no se sabe cómo habéis acabado aquí.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C__sch0_kfJy_e117_T7YN</Cell><Cell>There's no time. You're under attack!</Cell><Cell>No hay tiempo. ¡Os atacan!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C__sch0_kfJy_e131_CFPj</Cell><Cell>You abandoned your lord and he died. For that you'll swing on the gallows.</Cell><Cell>Habéis abandonado a vuestro señor y ha muerto. Por eso, acabaréis en el cadalso.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch1_oPBP_e1311_7rP3</Cell><Cell>Pick roses</Cell><Cell>Recoger rosas.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch1_oPBP_e597_vKdO</Cell><Cell>Get into the bath dressed.</Cell><Cell>Entrar vestido en el baño.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch1_oPBP_e598_e1oH</Cell><Cell>Take off the clothes and get into the bath.</Cell><Cell>Quitarse las ropas y entrar en el baño.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch2_dZo8_e1718_qbrs</Cell><Cell>A certain robber baron by the name of Wolflin of Kamberg has been pillaging farms in the fiefdom of Rattay with his band of renegades. The Lord of Rattay, Sir Hanush, takes a very dim view of his estates being ransacked, and so he's sent out a punitive expedition to deal with the outlaws. You are to take part.</Cell><Cell>Un presunto barón ladrón que responde al nombre de Wolflin de Kamberg ha estado saqueando las granjas del feudo de Rataje con su banda de renegados. El señor de Rataje, sir Hanush, no ve con buenos ojos que asalten su propiedad, y ha enviado una expedición de castigo a encargarse de los forajidos. Vos tomaréis parte.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch2_dZo8_e1719_yQKd</Cell><Cell>Your corps is about to attack Wolflin's encampment. It will be a tough battle, because the enemy is expecting you and your forces are more or less matched. Arm yourself well and may God guide your hand!</Cell><Cell>Vuestra compañía se dispone a atacar el campamento de Wolflin. Será una dura batalla, ya que el enemigo os espera y vuestras fuerzas están a la par. ¡Armaos bien y que el Señor guíe vuestra mano!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e1_FNiR</Cell><Cell>There's never a dull moment with the bold Sir Hans Capon. Before he can proceed with his knightly duties, he wants me to help him with a certain delicate matter of great urgency. </Cell><Cell>Uno nunca se aburre con el audaz sir Hans Capon. Antes de continuar con sus menesteres caballerescos, quiere que le ayude con un asunto delicado de extrema urgencia.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e11_pHxc</Cell><Cell>The beginning of a new adventure with Sir Hans is active at the end of the Capon quest line, culminating in the &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Robber Baron&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; assigment, which can be started after the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Questions and Answers.&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; Capon, however, has no time for amorous adventures during the battles towards the end of the game, so you won't be able to accept the quest from him until the very end, when Sir Hans arrives at the camp by Neuhof. If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc2Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon.</Cell><Cell>El comienzo de una nueva aventura con sir Hans se activa al final de la línea de misión de Capon, que culmina con el encargo de &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Barón ladrón&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;, que se puede iniciar después de la misión principal &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Preguntas y respuestas.&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; Capon, no obstante, no tiene tiempo para aventuras amorosas durante las batallas de la parte final del juego, por lo que no podrás aceptar su misión hasta el final, cuando sir Hans llega al campamento de Neuhof. Si no sabes dónde encontrarlo, busca el icono &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc2Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e13_J5OK</Cell><Cell>The beginning of a new adventure with Sir Hans is now active. All you have to do is go and talk to him. Capon, however, has no time for amorous adventures during the battles towards the end of the game, so you won't be able to accept the quest from him until the very end, when Sir Hans goes to the camp at Neuhof. If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc2Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon.</Cell><Cell>El comienzo de una nueva aventura con sir Hans no está activo. Solo tienes que ir a hablar con él. Capon, no obstante, no tiene tiempo para aventuras amorosas durante las batallas de la parte final del juego, por lo que no podrás aceptar su misión hasta el final, cuando sir Hans vaya al campamento de Neuhof. Si no sabes dónde encontrarlo, busca el icono &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc2Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e2_Kw10</Cell><Cell>Knowing that Sir Hans has somewhat different priorities than the other local lords, it wouldn't be unreasonable to assume that a damsel is involved. After our last dramatic adventure at the bathhouse, I'm curious - and more than a little apprehensive - as to what his latest escapade will be all about.</Cell><Cell>Dado que sir Hans tiene prioridades ligeramente diferentes a las de los demás señores de la zona, no sería absurdo deducir que hay alguna damisela involucrada. Después de nuestra dramática aventura en la casa de baños, tengo curiosidad, y quizá un cierto recelo, por saber en qué consistirá su última tropelía.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e2_NFgO</Cell><Cell>Wicked tongues say the heir to the Town of Rattay, young Sir Hans Capon, is an incorrigible seducer and whore-monger. A more charitable view is that he's just looking for love. The kind you can't buy at the bathhouse...</Cell><Cell>Las lenguas viperinas dicen que el heredero de la ciudad de Rataje, el joven sir Hans Capon, es un seductor incorregible y un putañero. Desde un punto de vista más benigno, podríamos decir que solo busca un poco de amor. Del tipo que se compra en la casa de baños...</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e3_XzI6</Cell><Cell>You know the heir to the Town of Rattay, young Sir Hans Capon, well enough to realise that there's more than a little truth to the rumours that he's an incorrigible seducer and whore-monger. But then again, maybe he's just looking for love. The kind you can't buy at the bathhouse...</Cell><Cell>Conocéis al heredero de la ciudad de Rataje, el joven sir Hans Capon, lo suficiente como para saber que los rumores que afirman que es un seductor incorregible y un putañero tienen gran parte de verdad. Pero en fin, quizá solo busca un poco de amor. Del tipo que se compra en la casa de baños...</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e4_iPlE</Cell><Cell>You have yet to make the acquaintance of the bold Sir Hans Capon, but once you do, be prepared to get drawn into his amorous adventures. You, a common blacksmith's son, will become His Lordship's herald, his messenger of love!</Cell><Cell>Aún no habéis entablado relación con el audaz sir Hans Capon, pero cuando lo hagáis, preparaos para veros involucrado en sus aventuras amorosas. Vos, el vulgar hijo de un herrero, os convertiréis en el heraldo de Su Excelencia, su mensajero del amor.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e6_YhfZ</Cell><Cell>You have a feeling that if you knew him better, you are very likely to get drawn into his amorous adventures. His Lordship's herald, his messenger of love - it has a ring to it!</Cell><Cell>Tenéis la sensación de que, si lo conocierais mejor, os veríais involucrado en sus aventuras amorosas. El heraldo de Su Excelencia, su mensajero del amor... ¡No suena mal!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e9_SGAF</Cell><Cell>Sir Hans Capon, the rightful heir to the Town of Rattay, dedicates most of his time to educating himself in matters knightly. He excels at hunting, combat and horseriding... or so he believes. He hasn't mastered the nobel game of chess, or even the more common game of dice, and as for poetry recitation, the time has come for him to work on that, if he's to win the heart of the maiden of his dreams.</Cell><Cell>Sir Hans Capon, el legítimo heredero de la ciudad de Rataje, dedica la mayor parte del tiempo a instruirse en asuntos de caballería. Destaca en la caza, el combate y la equitación... o eso cree. No ha dominado el noble arte de ajedrez, ni siquiera el común juego de dados. En cuanto a recitar poesía, le ha llegado la hora de afinar su talento, si de veras quiere conquistar el corazón de la doncella de sus sueños.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch19_T9qy_e10_XLxy</Cell><Cell>Begin combat (easy foe)</Cell><Cell>Iniciar el combate (enemigo fácil).</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch19_T9qy_e11_EBhq</Cell><Cell>Begin combat (intermediate foe)</Cell><Cell>Iniciar el combate (enemigo intermedio).</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch19_T9qy_e12_FPK6</Cell><Cell>Begin combat (hard foe)</Cell><Cell>Iniciar el combate (enemigo difícil).</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch19_T9qy_e13_h6fh</Cell><Cell>Begin combat with two foes</Cell><Cell>Iniciar el combate con dos enemigos.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch19_T9qy_e14_Bvcn</Cell><Cell>Begin battle (end of tutorial)</Cell><Cell>Iniciar combate (fin del tutorial).</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e23_l8le</Cell><Cell>Black clouds of strife are gathering, the thundering drums of war rumble across the land and the whole  kingdom awaits the next lightning bolt with bated breath. Not so the undaunted Sir Hanush, who decided to bolster morale with a regular tourney to keep his subjects fighting fit and distract them from the pervasive gloom. </Cell><Cell>Negras nubes de pesar se ciernen, los atronadores tambores de guerra resuenan por el territorio y el reino aguarda al próximo relámpago con el aliento contenido. No así el intrépido sir Hanush, que decidió elevar la moral organizando un torneo para que sus súbditos conservasen la práctica de combate y distraerlos de la desesperanza generalizada.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e24_Edki</Cell><Cell>The tourney takes place every few days by the Upper Castle in Rattay. All types of melee weapons are permitted, and the contest is open to combatants from all walks of life, even a lowborn, uneducated misfit like you. Just go and ask Sir Hans Capon about it and he'll tell you all you need to know.</Cell><Cell>El torneo se celebra cada pocos días en el castillo mayor de Rataje. Se permite todo tipo de armas cuerpo a cuerpo y pueden participar individuos de cualquier estamento, incluso plebeyos iletrados como tú. Ve a preguntar a sir Hans Capon sobre el asunto y te dirá todo lo que necesitas saber.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e26_cIeS</Cell><Cell>Black clouds of strife are gathering, the thundering drums of war rumble across the land and the whole  kingdom awaits the next lightning bolt with bated breath. Not so the undaunted Sir Hanush, who decided to bolster morale with a regular tourney to keep his subjects fighting fit and distract them from the pervasive gloom. </Cell><Cell>Negras nubes de pesar se ciernen, los atronadores tambores de guerra resuenan por el territorio y el reino aguarda al próximo relámpago con el aliento contenido. No así el intrépido sir Hanush, que decidió elevar la moral organizando un torneo para que sus súbditos conservasen la práctica de combate y distraerlos de la desesperanza generalizada.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e27_dQji</Cell><Cell>The tourney takes place every few days by the Upper Castle in Rattay. All types of melee weapons are permitted, and the contest is open to combatants from all walks of life, even a lowborn, uneducated misfit like you. Young Sir Hans Capon will tell you all you need to know about it. Once you've become better acquainted with him, that is. </Cell><Cell>El torneo se celebra cada pocos días en el castillo mayor de Rataje. Se permite todo tipo de armas cuerpo a cuerpo y pueden participar individuos de cualquier estamento, incluso plebeyos iletrados como tú. El joven sir Hans Capon te dirá todo lo que necesitas saber. Cuando establezcas mejores términos con él, claro.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e30_5QY2</Cell><Cell>The tournament convened by Sir Hanush takes place once every seven days at Rattay Upper Castle. The aim of the tourney is to test the skill of combatants will all kinds of weapons. It's intended for commoners, so you can enrol too. </Cell><Cell>El torneo convocado por sir Hanush se celebra cada siete días en el castillo mayor de Rataje. El objetivo del torneo es poner a prueba la habilidad de los combatientes con todo tipo de armas. Está destinado a los plebeyos, por lo que también puedes inscribirte. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e32_m7B8</Cell><Cell>After completing the side quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Next to Godliness&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; with Sir Hans, you can accept a new quest from him, which will launch an instance of the regular tournament. If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlcTournamentOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. If you've already progressed in the storyline as far as &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Epilogue&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;, you won't be able to accept the quest from Capon and the Tournament will launch on its own. the tournament will not take place while Sir Hanush is at war. </Cell><Cell>Después de completar la misión secundaria &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Rozando la divinidad&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; con sir Hans, puedes aceptar una nueva misión, que dará inicio a un torneo regular. Si no sabes dónde encontrarlo, busca el icono &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlcTournamentOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;. Si ya has progresado en la historia hasta el &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Epílogo&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;, no podrás aceptar la misión de Capon y el torneo se iniciará por sí solo. El torneo no se celebrará mientras sir Hanush esté en guerra. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e34_2Ipt</Cell><Cell>You can go and see Sir Hans and accept from him a new quest, which will launch a regular tournament. If you're not sure where to find Sir Hans, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlcTournamentOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. If you've already progressed in the storyline as far as &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Epilogue&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;, you won't be able to accept the quest from Capon and the tournament will launch on its own. The tournament will not take place while Sir Hanush is at war. </Cell><Cell>Puedes ir a ver a sir Hans y aceptar una nueva misión suya, que dará inicio a un torneo regular. Si no sabes dónde encontrarlo, busca el icono &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlcTournamentOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;. Si ya has progresado en la historia hasta el &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Epílogo&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;, no podrás aceptar la misión de Capon y el torneo se iniciará por sí solo. El torneo no se celebrará mientras sir Hanush esté en guerra. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e36_F5Dq</Cell><Cell>After launching the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; in Rattay, a tournament will be automatically launched every week at Rattay Upper Castle. The tournament will not take place, however, while Sir Hanush is at war. </Cell><Cell>Después de iniciar la misión principal &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Despertar&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; en Rataje, se dará comienzo a un torneo automáticamente cada semana en el castillo mayor de Rataje. Sin embargo, el torneo no se llevará a cabo mientras sir Hanush esté en guerra. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap27_PxIe_sch0_c5YT_e131_Qgwo</Cell><Cell>Quest started</Cell><Cell>Misión iniciada</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap27_PxIe_sch0_c5YT_e132_70UZ</Cell><Cell>Blessing of overseer</Cell><Cell>La bendición del prior</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap27_PxIe_sch0_c5YT_e132_gMEy</Cell><Cell>Chasing Zmola</Cell><Cell>La persecución de Zmola</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap27_PxIe_sch0_c5YT_e132_H3Q2</Cell><Cell>Disappearance of Leshek</Cell><Cell>La desaparición de Leshek</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap32_sch1_Yhte_e2_eyDY</Cell><Cell>Wayfarer</Cell><Cell>Caminante</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap32_sch1_Yhte_e4_dQKb</Cell><Cell>Examine</Cell><Cell>Examinar</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap32_sch1_Yhte_e5_yZbc</Cell><Cell>Ignore</Cell><Cell>Ignorar</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap32_sch1_Yhte_e7_obSX</Cell><Cell>Stop  </Cell><Cell>Parar</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap32_sch1_Yhte_e8_5efG</Cell><Cell>Flee</Cell><Cell>Huir</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e52_pzSy</Cell><Cell>To your surprise, you've found there are some interesting papers amongst your things. Most likely they were concealed in the saddlebag of the horse you escaped from Skalitz on. It seems the men of the Talmberg garrison assumed they were yours and put them in your trunk. But how would a common blacksmith's son come by such documents? After all, you can't even read! The mysterious documents have an ancient seal that testifies to the noble and ancient origin of their author. </Cell><Cell>Para tu sorpresa, descubres entre tus cosas una serie de documentos interesantes. Es probable que estuvieran ocultos en las alforjas del caballo al huir de Skalice. Parece que los hombres de la guarnición de Talmberk dieron por hecho que eran tuyos y los colocaron en tu baúl. ¿Pero por qué tendría el hijo de un vulgar herrero esos documentos? ¡Si ni siquiera sabes leer! Los misteriosos documentos tienen un sello antiguo que atestigua el origen noble y ancestral de su autor.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e53_nsaj</Cell><Cell>You're not able to make any sense out of their content, but, luckily for you, you're not the first one to examine them. And whoever it was that read them, that learned person created a number of simple sketches based on their content, which look like descriptions of places where rare items of clothing and armour are hidden! You've put the papers safely away in your trunk, where they're waiting until you have time to study them more closely.</Cell><Cell>El contenido no tiene sentido para ti, pero, por suerte, no eres el primero que los examina. Quien fuera el que los leyó, era un erudito que creó una serie de bosquejos basados en su contenido, algo parecido a descripciones de lugares donde se ocultan objetos de vestuario y armaduras raros. Colocas los documentos a salvo en tu baúl, a la espera de disponer de tiempo para estudiarlos más detenidamente.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e56_v6wf</Cell><Cell>A legend is circulating in the province about stashes containing magnificent Warhorse armour. Many people have searched for it, but in vain. With a little effort and the grace of God, perhaps you can succeed in finding the armour and donning it to assist you in fighting the good fight!</Cell><Cell>Por la provincia circula una leyenda sobre alijos que contienen una magnífica armadura de corcel. Muchos la han buscado, mas en vano. Con un poco de esfuerzo y la gracia de Dios, quizá vos podáis conseguir encontrar la armadura y vestirla como ayuda en el combate.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e58_tSzl</Cell><Cell>The first part of the Warhorse armour and five treasure maps will appear in your universal trunk after launching the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; in Rattay Mill. You can access your trunk from any home or lodgings you have in the world.</Cell><Cell>La primera parte de la armadura de corcel y cinco mapas del tesoro aparecerán en el baúl universal tras iniciar la misión principal &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Despertar&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; en el molino de Rataje. Se puede acceder al baúl desde cualquier casa o vivienda que tengas en el mundo.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e60_b6T9</Cell><Cell>The first part of the Warhorse armour and five more treasure maps are stored in your universal trunk in Rattay Mill. You can access your trunk from any home or lodgings you have in the world.</Cell><Cell>La primera parte de la armadura de corcel y cinco mapas del tesoro se guardan en el baúl universal en el molino de Rataje. Se puede acceder al baúl desde cualquier casa o vivienda que tengas en el mundo.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e29_B18G</Cell><Cell>Although you hardly ventured beyond Skalitz your whole life, now and again you heard tidings from travelling merchants and wayfarers about goings on in the outside world - the big harvest festival in Merhojed, the rebuilding of Sasau Monastery and stories about an abandoned village in the woods near Talmberg. </Cell><Cell>Aunque en muy contadas ocasiones te has aventurado más allá de las fronteras de Skalice en tu vida, de vez en cuando has oído relatos de viajeros y mercaderes sobre lo que sucede en el mundo exterior: el gran festival de la cosecha en Mrchojedy, la reconstrucción del monasterio de Sázava, e historias sobre una aldea abandonada en el bosque cercano a Talmberk.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e30_zOG0</Cell><Cell>That village is called Pribyslavitz, and for years it has lain in ruins. You've always been curious about it - where exactly it is, what mysteries it conceals and why no one ever went back there to live. You're determined to go there and explore the village, just as soon as you and the local lords have dealt with the bandits.</Cell><Cell>Esa aldea se llama Přibyslavice, y está en ruinas desde hace años. Siempre has sentido curiosidad por ella... dónde se encuentra, qué misterios oculta y por qué nadie ha vuelto a vivir a ella. Estás resuelto a ir a explorar la aldea en cuanto tú y los señores locales os hayáis encargado de los bandidos.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e32_eqgM</Cell><Cell>After you and your comrades-in-arms drove the bandits out of Pribyslavitz, the village was once again left to be slowly swallowed up by the woods. A shame - before being plundered by a renegade lord, it was no doubt a sprawling, bustling hamlet, judging by the size of the ruined church there, which is all that's left as a reminder of its former prosperity.</Cell><Cell>Después de que tú y tus compañeros de armas expulsarais a los bandidos de Přibyslavice, la aldea quedó de nuevo abandonada para ser devorada por el bosque. Una pena. Antes de ser saqueada por un noble renegado, fue sin duda una villa floreciente y bulliciosa, a juzgar por el tamaño de las ruinas de la iglesia, único recuerdo de su pasada prosperidad.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e33_mdnB</Cell><Cell>You always wondered why the folk never went back to live there, so you were pleasantly surprised to learn that Sir Divish has plans for his former hamlet. You don't know exactly what he has in mind, but you'll be glad to have a hand in it. You're sure to find out in Talmberg what needs to be done.</Cell><Cell>Siempre te has preguntado por qué nadie volvió jamás a vivir allí, así que te sorprendió gratamente saber que sir Divish tenía planes para la vieja aldea. No sabes qué tiene en mente exactamente, pero estarás encantado de ayudar. Estás convencido de que en Talmberk averiguarás lo que hay que hacer.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e41_Z7m2</Cell><Cell>Pribyslavitz, a sprawling, long-abandoned village, is now swallowed up by the woods. You always wondered what secrets it concealed and why the villagers never returned there, and so you were pleasantly surprised when Sir Divish told you he had plans for the old settlement. </Cell><Cell>Přibyslavice, una dispersa aldea abandonada desde hace tiempo, ha sido engullida por el bosque. Siempre te has preguntado qué secretos ocultaba y por qué nadie volvió jamás a vivir allí, así que te sorprendió gratamente saber que sir Divish tenía planes para el viejo asentamiento. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e43_Sx5N</Cell><Cell>Sir Divish enlists your help in rebuilding Pribyslavitz after the bandits have been driven out of the hamlet in the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Baptism of Fire.&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc1Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. However, you will temporarily not be able to launch or continue playing the DLC during any battle quests.</Cell><Cell>Sir Divish solicita tu ayuda para reconstruir Přibyslavice después de que los bandidos fuesen expulsados de la aldea en la misión principal &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Bautismo de fuego.&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; Si no sabes dónde encontrarlo, busca el icono &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc1Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;. Sin embargo, temporalmente no podrás iniciar ni seguir jugando el DLC durante las misiones de batalla.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e45_P5pu</Cell><Cell>Go and see Sir Divish, who wants you to help rebuild Pribyslavitz.  If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc1Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. Bear in mind, though, that it will not be possible to temporarily resume or complete the rebuilding during any battles. </Cell><Cell>Ve a ver a sir Divish, que solicita tu ayuda para reconstruir Přibyslavice. Si no sabes dónde encontrarlo, busca el icono &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc1Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;. Pero ten en cuenta que no será posible reanudar ni completar temporalmente la reconstrucción durante las batallas. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch5_mZpP_e507_HUZ7</Cell><Cell>A few days later.</Cell><Cell>Unos días después.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e11_xZNi</Cell><Cell>You can get a dog from Theresa at Rattay Mill, but only after launching the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;.</Cell><Cell>Podéis conseguir un perro de manos de Theresa, en el molino de Rataje, pero solo después de activar la misión principal &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Despertar&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e13_pa33</Cell><Cell>Theresa's story is now active. You can launch the quest line by talking to Theresa. You'll be led to her by &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4TheresaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell><Cell>Ahora la historia de Theresa está activa. Podéis activar la línea de misiones si habláis con Theresa. &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4TheresaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; os llevará hasta ella.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e17_jskP</Cell><Cell>Theresa is now looking after a dog at Rattay Mill. She's hoping you take it over, because her uncle, Miller Peshek, doesn't like the animal. Go and see Theresa and offer to help.</Cell><Cell>Ahora Theresa está cuidando de un perro en el molino de Rataje. Espera que vos os hagáis cargo de él porque a su tío Peshek, el molinero, no le gustan los animales. Id a ver a Theresa y ofrecedle vuestra ayuda.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e21_BK5Z</Cell><Cell>A difficult fate awaits Johanka. To find out more, go and visit her at the monastery infirmary and look for &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4JohankaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;</Cell><Cell>Un destino difícil espera a Johanka. Para descubrir más, id a visitarla a la enfermería del monasterio y buscad a &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4JohankaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e3_k92t</Cell><Cell>Armed with fortitude and dignity, she faces the coming days with a smile on her lips. And since God moves in mysterious ways, none of us can know the lot we shall have to bear. But it is often those of whom we least expect it who encounter an extraordinary destiny...</Cell><Cell>Armada con fortaleza y dignidad, se enfrenta a los días siguientes con una sonrisa en los labios. Y como los caminos del Señor son inescrutables, ninguno podíamos sospechar lo que nos esperaba. Pero a menudo es a aquellos de los que menos esperamos los que se encuentran con un destino extraordinario...</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e5_oXts</Cell><Cell>You're the son of a blacksmith, whose life centred around the forge, not farming and livestock. It's not as if you ever missed cattle or pigs, but to have a dog of your own? Now that would be nice...</Cell><Cell>Sois el hijo del herrero, vuestra vida ha estado centrada en la forja, nada de granjas ni ganado. Tampoco es que hayáis echado de menos a las reses o los cerdos pero, ¿un perro? Eso estaría bien...</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e7_tMbu</Cell><Cell>Theresa's story will be available to you once you launch the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. Then all you have to do is talk to Theresa in Rattay Mill. You'll be led to her by &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4TheresaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell><Cell>La historia de Theresa estará disponible cuando iniciéis la misión principal &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Despertar&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. Después solo tendréis que hablar con Theresa en el molino de Rataje. &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4TheresaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; os llevará hasta ella.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e9_AUe9</Cell><Cell>A difficult fate awaits Johanka. To find out more about it, you must have completed the side quests &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Pestilence&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;In God's Hands&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;, whether successfully or not. You will get to &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Pestilence&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; from the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Questions and Answers&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;In God's Hands&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; is assigned to you by Johanka, who is to be found at Sasau Monastery. Once you've completed those quests, all you have to do is visit Johanka again, where you will be guided by &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4JohankaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell><Cell>A Johanka le espera un destino difícil. Para descubrir más acerca de él hay que completar las misiones secundarias &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Pestilencia&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; y &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;En manos de Dios&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. Da igual si se terminan con éxito o no. &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Pestilencia&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; se consigue desde la misión principal &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Preguntas y respuestas&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;En manos de Dios&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; la asigna Johanka, que está en el monasterio de Sázava. Cuando se hayan completado esas misiones solo hay que volver a visitar a Johanka, adonde se es guiado por &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4JohankaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch35_xmhH_e337_KWau</Cell><Cell>Preacher</Cell><Cell>Predicador</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e13_bdlz</Cell><Cell>Hold-up</Cell><Cell>Asalto</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e14_Ii0w</Cell><Cell>Don't interfere in it</Cell><Cell>No interferir</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e18_AlMX</Cell><Cell>Fight</Cell><Cell>Luchar</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e19_lmga</Cell><Cell>Watch the battle</Cell><Cell>Observar la batalla</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e19_velx</Cell><Cell>Flee</Cell><Cell>Huir</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e23_Onaq</Cell><Cell>Untie</Cell><Cell>Desatar.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e497_Jylz</Cell><Cell>Carcass on the Road</Cell><Cell>Cadáver en el camino</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e498_udhL</Cell><Cell>Stop</Cell><Cell>Parar</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e499_Gkvg</Cell><Cell>Ride around and ignore it</Cell><Cell>Esquivarlo e ignorarlo</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e500_6K58</Cell><Cell>Go around and ignore it</Cell><Cell>Esquivarlo e ignorarlo</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e503_wcog</Cell><Cell>Have a chat</Cell><Cell>Tener una charla</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e504_4I17</Cell><Cell>Flee</Cell><Cell>Huir</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e514_FS5n</Cell><Cell>Look at the weapon</Cell><Cell>Mirar al arma</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch45_nmtr_e95_BhsL</Cell><Cell>Give the convict a drink.</Cell><Cell>Darle de beber al convicto</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch47_94Dl_e1_W2wk</Cell><Cell>Chase</Cell><Cell>Perseguir.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e1_O1wc</Cell><Cell>Attack on the road</Cell><Cell>Ataque en el camino</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e16_ewho</Cell><Cell>Scout</Cell><Cell>Explorar</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e17_PQwb</Cell><Cell>Halt</Cell><Cell>Pararse</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e18_2dRv</Cell><Cell>Run away</Cell><Cell>Huir</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e19_RGfd</Cell><Cell>Avoid</Cell><Cell>Evitar</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch15_T7No_e6_QlXw</Cell><Cell>Too many of your men have died.</Cell><Cell>Han muerto demasiados de tus hombres.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch2_iRf2_e11_6IvY</Cell><Cell>The early 15th century was a time of turmoil in the Holy Roman Empire, which had flourished under the late Emperor Charles IV, but now, with his son Wenceslas “the Idle“ on the Bohemian throne, was falling into disarray.

</Cell><Cell>La primera parte del siglo XV fue una época turbulenta para el Sacro Imperio Romano que había florecido durante el mandato del emperador Carlos IV. Ahora, con su hijo Wenceslao «el Indolente» en el trono de Bohemia, estaba sumiéndose en el desorden.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch2_iRf2_e12_U8N0</Cell><Cell>The King’s inactivity angered many of the nobility, as well as his half-brother, King Sigismund of Hungary, who decided to take drastic steps to restore order to the Empire…
</Cell><Cell>La dejadez del Rey enfureció a la nobleza, así como a su medio hermano, el rey Segismundo de Hungría, que decidió tomar medidas drásticas para restaurar el orden en el Imperio...</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch2_iRf2_e12_vkUl</Cell><Cell>Silver Skalitz, 1403</Cell><Cell>Skalice Plateada, 1403</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch2_iRf2_e990_QBhT</Cell><Cell>Throw manure.</Cell><Cell>Lanzar estiércol.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch22_LAqJ_e810_xbED</Cell><Cell>Skip mass</Cell><Cell>Saltarse la misa.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch22_LAqJ_e815_OUNX</Cell><Cell>Eat</Cell><Cell>Comer.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch25_kJcP_e58_PAkf</Cell><Cell>Raise the portcullis</Cell><Cell>Subir el rastrillo.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch25_kJcP_e9_mUC2</Cell><Cell>Before the return to Talmberg</Cell><Cell>Antes de regresar a Talmberk</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch28_w7oB_e271_IWz9</Cell><Cell>You did not arrive at the battleground.</Cell><Cell>No habéis llegado al campo de batalla.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch28_w7oB_e273_wPqw</Cell><Cell>You fled the battlefield.</Cell><Cell>Has huido del campo de batalla.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch7_9t19_e58_Suu4</Cell><Cell>In the castle.</Cell><Cell>En el castillo.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch7_9t19_e8_Zrcd</Cell><Cell>Run!</Cell><Cell>¡Corred!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch7_nFPk_e311_GKf6</Cell><Cell>Zbyshek killed you while you were unconscious.</Cell><Cell>Zbyshek os ha matado mientras estabais inconsciente.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch8_Votg_e104_iWG2</Cell><Cell>A FEW DELIRIOUS DAYS LATER…</Cell><Cell>UNOS DÍAS DE DELIRIO DESPUÉS...</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch8_Votg_e186_2516</Cell><Cell>AND EVEN LATER…</Cell><Cell>Y, AÚN MÁS TARDE...</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch9_FEsU_e1491_2eLv</Cell><Cell>Inspect</Cell><Cell>Inspeccionar</Cell></Row>
</Table>