<Table>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc4_sch1_AMrB_e10_MM0d</Cell><Cell>Option 2 - neither Pestilince nor Wounded Soul was started - help Radzig and look for survivors from Skalitz; rumours, Johanka is in Sasau, Pestilence completed, but not Wounded Soul - similar to first - just go to Johanka and see if she needs help</Cell><Cell>Option 2 : Ni Le fléau, ni Une âme meurtrie ont été entreprises. Aidez Radzig à chercher les survivants de Skalice ; on raconte que Jeanne est à Sasau. Le fléau accomplie, mais pas Une âme meurtrie. Comme la première option, allez auprès de Jeanne à Sasau pour voir si elle a besoin d'aide.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc4_sch1_AMrB_e11_Ebyp</Cell><Cell>Option 3 Pestilence underway, Wounded Soul underway - help Merhojed locals and Johanka</Cell><Cell>Option 3 : Le fléau en cours, Une âme meurtrie en cours. Aidez Jeanne et les citoyens de Merhojed.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc4_sch1_AMrB_e9_8Fnr</Cell><Cell>Option 1 - Pestilence and Wounded Soul are completed - go to Johanka, she'll be happy to see you</Cell><Cell>Option 1 : Le fléau et Une âme meurtrie ont été accomplies. Retournez voir Jeanne, elle sera contente de vous voir.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc4_sch17_NeWe_e146_Y9bJ</Cell><Cell>You've  unlocked the perk First Aid II.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_first_aid_perk.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;Using bandages is now more effective and you can also take advantage of your healing skills in dialogues.</Cell><Cell>Vous avez débloqué l'atout Premiers soins II.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_first_aid_perk.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;Utiliser des bandages est encore plus efficace et vos talents de soin vous ouvrent des possibilités de dialogues.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc4_sch18_FJ22_e81_iK55</Cell><Cell>You've acquired a dagger and the perk Stealth Kill&lt;br/&gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_stealth_perk.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;If you sneak up on a foe from behind unobserved, you can take him down by holding $attack3;.</Cell><Cell>Vous avez obtenu une dague ainsi que l'atout Meurtre furtif&lt;br/&gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_stealth_perk.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;Si vous vous faufilez près d'un ennemi par derrière sans qu'il ne vous remarque, vous pouvez l'abattre en maintenant $attack3;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch27_whpB_e768_aPhc</Cell><Cell>Press $read_toggle; while reading the herbarium to toggle between the herb list and the recipe list. Press $read_select; while on a recipe to put all the ingredients required for that recipe on the shelves.</Cell><Cell>Appuyez sur  $read_toggle; lors de la lecture de l'herbier pour bascule entre la liste des herbes et celle des recettes. Appuyez sur $read_select; sur une recette pour ajouter tous les ingrédients requis pour cette recette sur les étagères.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch27_whpB_e781_ZMKy</Cell><Cell>Bellows are controlled by the $alch_use_bag; key.</Cell><Cell>Les soufflets sont contrôlés avec le bouton $alch_use_bag;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch30_m-Hk_e637_8z_C</Cell><Cell>The cursor grows in size to indicate that you approach the sweetspot. You can start to rotate the lock as soon as the cursor changes colour. &amp;lt;img src="Textures/lockpicking1"&amp;gt; Rotate the lock with $lock_dir_fwd; . The sweetspot rotates with the lock, so you will have to move the cursor to stay within the sweetspot. &amp;lt;img src="Textures/lockpicking2"&amp;gt; Your lockpick will break if you fail to keep the cursor within the sweetspot.</Cell><Cell>Le curseur grossit à mesure que vous vous approchez du point sensible. Vous pouvez commencer à tourner la serrure dès que le curseur change de couleur. &amp;lt;img src="Textures/lockpicking1"&amp;gt; Tourner la serrure avec $lock_dir_fwd; Le point sensible tourne en même temps que la serrure, donc vous aurez à bouger le curseur pour rester à l'intérieur de la zone sensible. &amp;lt;img src="Textures/lockpicking2"&amp;gt; Votre crochet se cassera si vous échouez à maintenant le curseur dans la zone sensible.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e151_dpUT</Cell><Cell>Move around the battlefield by $ui_left; and $ui_right;, look around by mouse. Cursor  will lock on enemy. You can unlock easily by sprinting or by pressing a mouse wheel.</Cell><Cell>Déplacez-vous sur le champ de bataille avec $ui_left; et $ui_right;, regardez autour de vous avec la souris. Le curseur va se verrouiller sur l'ennemi. Il peut facilement être déverrouillé en sprintant ou en appuyant sur la molette de la souris.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e167_4IhZ</Cell><Cell>Move around the battlefield with your left stick. Use a right  stick to look around, cursor will lock on enemy. You can unlock the enemy by holding the stick or by sprinting with $sprint;</Cell><Cell>Déplacez-vous sur le champ de bataille à l'aide du stick gauche. Utilisez le stick droit pour regarder autour de vous, le curseur va se verrouiller sur l'ennemi.  Vous pouvez déverrouiller l'ennemi en maintenant le stick ou en sprintant avec $sprint;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e169_60Ic</Cell><Cell>You can change your attack zone by mouse.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Aim for the head: &amp;lt;img src="Textures/ccursor0"&amp;gt; &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Slashing attack: $attack1_mouse;</Cell><Cell>Vous pouvez modifier votre zone d'attaque à l'aide de la souris. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Visez la tête: &amp;lt;img src="Textures/ccursor0"&amp;gt; &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Coup d'épée: $attack1_mouse;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e170_VzFb</Cell><Cell>You can change your attack zone by right stick.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Aim for the head: &amp;lt;img src="Textures/ccursor0"&amp;gt; &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Slashing attack: $attack1;</Cell><Cell>Vous pouvez modifier votre zone d'attaque à l'aide du joystick droit. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Visez la tête: &amp;lt;img src="Textures/ccursor0"&amp;gt; &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Coup d'épée: $attack1;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e172_mUC1</Cell><Cell>Change zones by mouse, you will also change your guard automatically. Slash with the left mouse button, stab with the right.</Cell><Cell>Modifiez la zone avec la souris, votre garde changera également de manière automatique. Donnez un coup d'épée avec le bouton gauche de la souris, poignardez avec le bouton droit.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e173_yZEn</Cell><Cell>Change zones by right stick, you will also change your guard automatically. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src="Textures/xi_thumbry"&amp;gt; &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; $attack1; slash&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;$attack2; stab</Cell><Cell>Modifiez la zone avec le stick droit, votre garde changera automatiquement. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src="Textures/xi_thumbry"&amp;gt; &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; $attack1; coup d'épée&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;$attack2; poignarder</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e175_3FoO</Cell><Cell>Hold $block; to keep blocking. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Blocking slows  down stamina regeneration!</Cell><Cell>Maintenez $block; pour conserver le blocage. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Le blocage ralentit la restauration de l'endurance!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e177_GipJ</Cell><Cell>Try to time your $block; to a moment when enemy starts his attack. That's parry!</Cell><Cell>Essayez d'appuyer sur $block; pile au moment où l'ennemi début son attaque. C'est une parade!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e178_a6aP</Cell><Cell>Now!</Cell><Cell>Maintenant!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e179_rCcC</Cell><Cell>Well done!</Cell><Cell>Bien joué!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e180_mHoO</Cell><Cell>Too late…</Cell><Cell>Trop tard…</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e182_zL0l</Cell><Cell>You can counterattack immediatelly after succesfull parry.</Cell><Cell>Vous pouvez contre-attaquer immédiatement après une parade réussie.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e184_8PCU</Cell><Cell>Block with $block; &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Parry is disabled for now…</Cell><Cell>Bloquez avec $block; &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; La parade est pour l'instant désactivée…</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e186_4po3</Cell><Cell>The key is to change attack zone in the middle of an attack! &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Try some combos:&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; $attack1_mouse; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor0&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor2&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor3&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;or&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; $attack1_mouse; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor1&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor3&amp;quot;&amp;gt; then stab.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;or&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; $attack1_mouse; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor0&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor1&amp;quot;&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor4&amp;quot;&amp;gt; then stab</Cell><Cell>Le but est de modifier sa zone d'attaque au milieu d'une attaque! &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Tentez des combos:&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; $attack1_mouse; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor0&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor2&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor3&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;ou&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; $attack1_mouse; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor1&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor3&amp;quot;&amp;gt; puis poignardez.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;ou&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; $attack1_mouse; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor0&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor1&amp;quot;&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor4&amp;quot;&amp;gt; puis poignardez</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e187_zU5t</Cell><Cell>The key is to change attack zone in the middle of an attack! &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Try some combos:&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; $attack1; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor0&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor2&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor3&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;or&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; $attack1; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor1&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor3&amp;quot;&amp;gt; then $attack2;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;or&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; $attack1; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor0&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor1&amp;quot;&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor4&amp;quot;&amp;gt; then $attack2;</Cell><Cell>Le but est de modifier sa zone d'attaque au milieu d'une attaque! &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Tentez des combos:&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; $attack1; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor0&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor2&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor3&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;ou&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; $attack1; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor1&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor3&amp;quot;&amp;gt; puis $attack2;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;ou&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; $attack1; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor0&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor1&amp;quot;&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;Textures/ccursor4&amp;quot;&amp;gt; puis $attack2;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e189_Y6cR</Cell><Cell>As soon as your enemy starts his attack, try to move to the side.</Cell><Cell>Essayez de faire un pas de côté dès que votre ennemi débute son attaque.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e191_ESJt</Cell><Cell>Time for feints! By holding the attack button, you raise your weapon, you strike with release. If you change the attack zone before the actual strike, you can trick your opponent into guarding wrong side. Feel free to try it for a while.</Cell><Cell>C'est le moment de feinter! Levez votre arme en maintenant le bouton d'attaque, puis frappez en le relâchant. Si vous modifiez la zone d'attaque avant d'atteindre votre adversaire, vous pouvez le piéger pour qu'il effectue son blocage du mauvais côté. N'hésitez pas à l'essayer.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap0_sch38_cdLq_e193_VZ8n</Cell><Cell>Free fight! Now you can try all you've learned. The combat ends in three minutes. You can finish it earlier by leaving the combat area.</Cell><Cell>Combat d'entraînement! Vous pouvez désormais essayer tout ce que vous avez appris. Le combat prendra fin dans trois minutes. Vous pouvez l'interrompre plus vite en quittant la zone de combat.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e1_xERA</Cell><Cell>$h;BREWERY$h_end;You've built yourself a brewery and from now on the innkeeper will be able to brew a local beer. Every time a new batch is brewed, you can pick it up from the vat on top of the kiln at the brewery. Drink responsibly!&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/1057.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Pribyslavitz Boar$font_end;</Cell><Cell>$h;BRASSERIE$h_end;Vous avez construit une brasserie et dorénavant, votre aubergiste va produire une bière locale. Vous pouvez en récupérer à chaque nouveau brassin dans la cuve sur le four, à la brasserie. À consommer avec modération !&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/1057.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;La Sanglier de Pribyslavice$font_end;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e101_3j95</Cell><Cell>$h;OVEREATING$h_end;You've eaten too much! You won't be hungry for a much longer time now, but you'll be clumsy until you've digested everything.</Cell><Cell>$h;TROP MANGER$h_end;Vous avez trop mangé ! Vous n'aurez plus faim avant un petit moment, mais vous serez maladroit et lourd le temps de la digestion.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e11_bw0R</Cell><Cell>$h;QUESTS$h_end;Most of the quests can be completed in different ways - some people can be persuaded, some can be robbed. And if you'd rather not beat around the bush, violence can also be a solution.</Cell><Cell>$h;QUÊTES$h_end;La plupart des quêtes peuvent être accomplies de plusieurs façons différentes — vous pouvez persuader certaines personnes, et en voler d'autres. Et si vous n'êtes pas du genre à tourner autour du pot, la violence peut également être une solution.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e13_YuQX</Cell><Cell>$h;QUEST LOG$h_end;You can find all information about the quests in the $font_color;log$font_end;. And for clarity they are also indicated on the $font_color;map$font_end;, as well as on the compass at the top of the screen. $p;{$ui_toggle_quest;|$ui_open_quest^;}&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;$font_color;Questlog$font_end;$p;{$ui_toggle_map;|$ui_open_map;}&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;$font_color;Map$font_end;</Cell><Cell>$h;JOURNAL DE QUÊTES$h_end;Vous pouvez retrouver toutes les informations sur les quêtes dans le $font_color;journal$font_end;. Par souci d'ergonomie, elles sont également indiquées sur la $font_color;carte$font_end; ainsi que sur la boussole située en haut de l'écran. $p;{$ui_toggle_quest;|$ui_open_quest^;}&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;$font_color;Journal de quêtes$font_end;$p;{$ui_toggle_map;|$ui_open_map;}&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;$font_color;Carte$font_end;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e15_8M2H</Cell><Cell>$h;SHOPPING$h_end;In shops, you first have to put your purchases $use; into your $font_color;basket$font_end; and then either confirm the purchase $ui_reset; or try to haggle.$p;The amount you have to pay is always shown at the top of the screen.</Cell><Cell>$h;ACHATS$h_end;Dans les boutiques, vous devez d'abord placer les objets $use; dans votre $font_color;panier$font_end; puis confirmer vos achats $ui_reset; ou essayer de marchander.$p;Le montant total est indiqué en haut de l'écran.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e17_keCW</Cell><Cell>When haggling, you try to reach the best possible price without trying the trader's patience to the limits.$p;The slider shows the current price that's acceptable to the trader and the icon below it his level of annoyance.</Cell><Cell>En marchandant, essayez d'atteindre le meilleur prix possible sans trop jouer avec la patience du marchand. $p;Le curseur montre le prix actuellement acceptable pour le marchand et l'icône en dessous, son niveau d'irritation.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e174_dsC8</Cell><Cell>$h;HORSE$h_end;You can whistle to call your horse by pressing $call_horse;$p;You can move some items from your inventory to your horse's saddlebags - (in $font_color;Inventory$font_end; press $ui_reset;).$p;You can increase the capacity of your horse's inventory by getting a better saddle or a stronger horse. </Cell><Cell>$h;CHEVAL$h_end;Vous pouvez siffler pour appeler votre cheval en appuyant sur $call_horse;$p;Vous pouvez transférer certains objets de votre inventaire vers les sacoches de votre cheval — (dans l'$font_color;inventaire$font_end;, appuyez sur $ui_reset;).$p;Vous pouvez augmenter la capacité d'inventaire de votre monture en vous procurant une meilleure selle ou un cheval plus robuste.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e19_zic4</Cell><Cell>The player's character and abilities are determined by the stats, skills and perks you will find in the Player tab{ $ui_toggle_player;|}.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt;Henry basically develops his abilities constantly simply by using them. Once every few level ups the player can choose a specific perk that will allow him to further specialise in a given skill.</Cell><Cell>La personnalité et les capacités de votre personnage sont déterminées par les statistiques, compétences et atouts que vous pouvez retrouver dans l'onglet Personnage{ $ui_toggle_player;|}.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt;Henry progresse en utilisant ces capacités. Lorsqu'il atteint certains seuils de niveau, vous pouvez choisir un atout qui va lui permettre de se spécialiser dans une compétence particulière.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e20_duQ2</Cell><Cell>$h;SAVING THE GAME$h_end;The game saves automatically at important moments during quests and when you sleep in your own bed. To save it immediately, drink Saviour Schnapps.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/savegamium.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Saviour Schnapps$font_end;</Cell><Cell>$h;SAUVEGARDER VOTRE PARTIE$h_end;Votre partie est sauvegardée automatiquement à certains moments clés d'une quête et lorsque vous dormez dans votre propre lit. Si vous voulez sauvegarder manuellement, vous devez boire la potion Schnaps du sauveur.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/savegamium.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Schnaps du sauveur$font_end;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e202_Mi8E</Cell><Cell>$h;FOOD-POSIONING$h_end;You've been poisoned! Be careful what you eat and drink - spoiled food can posion you.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_food_poison_buff.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Food-poisoning$font_end;</Cell><Cell>$h;INTOXICATION ALIMENTAIRE$h_end;Vous avez été victime d'une intoxication alimentaire ! Faites attention à la nourriture et aux boissons que vous ingérez. La nourriture avariée peut vous empoisonner.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_food_poison_buff.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Intoxication alimentaire$font_end;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e21_6oDO</Cell><Cell>$h;INVENTORY$h_end;In the Inventory tab you will see all your equipment with detailed descriptions. Here you can also change your character's outfit.$p;{$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;}&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;$font_color;Inventory$font_end;</Cell><Cell>$h;INVENTAIRE$h_end;Vous pouvez retrouver dans l'onglet Inventaire tout votre équipement avec une description détaillée. C'est dans ce menu que vous avez la possibilité de changer la tenue de votre personnage.$p;{$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;}&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;$font_color;Inventaire$font_end;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e21_q48i</Cell><Cell>You can choose perks that improve or change the gameplay and the use of specific skills. You can select the perks in the Player tab{ $ui_toggle_player;| $ui_open_player^;}.</Cell><Cell>Vous pouvez choisir des atouts qui améliorent ou modifient la jouabilité et l'utilisation de compétences spécifiques. Vous pouvez les sélectionner dans l'onglet Personnage{ $ui_toggle_player;| $ui_open_player^;}.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e211_eTep</Cell><Cell>$h;TROPHY$h_end;Hunted game is a great source of meat. But if the hunter wants to get a trophy or offal, he has to learn the appropriate perk. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/antlers.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/butcher.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/tanner.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/tusks.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;</Cell><Cell>$h;TROPHÉE$h_end;Le gibier constitue la meilleure des viandes. Mais si le chasseur désire obtenir un trophée ou des abats, il doit commencer par apprendre l'atout correspondant. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/antlers.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/butcher.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/tanner.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/tusks.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e220_OYNU</Cell><Cell>Different weapon types are suited to different situations. Swords are universal - they are good for both piercing and slashing attacks.&lt;br/&gt;Axes are heavier, best for slashing attacks, but slower than swords.&lt;br/&gt;Maces and hammers deliver devastating crushing attacks - especially against plate armour, but are unwieldy.&lt;br/&gt;Polearms are superb weapons - their long reach and heavy attack power make them extremely effective. However, they're to unwieldy to carry in your inventory.</Cell><Cell>Les différentes catégories d'armes sont destinées à des situations bien distinctes. Les épées sont universelles, elles servent aussi bien à la taille qu'à l'estoc.&lt;br/&gt;Les haches sont quant à elles plus lourdes, mieux adaptées à la taille, mais plus lentes.&lt;br/&gt;Les marteaux et autres gourdins servent à faire des dégâts dévastateurs, notamment contre les armures de plates, mais sont difficiles à manier.&lt;br/&gt;Les armes d'hast sont excellentes : leur longue portée et leurs violentes attaques en font des armes extrêmement efficaces. Elles prennent néanmoins de la place dans l'inventaire.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e224_Yril</Cell><Cell>$h;DRAWN WEAPON$h_end;Drawn weapon causes fear amongst villagers. In cities they may even call a guard on you!</Cell><Cell>$h;ARME DÉGAINÉE$h_end;Une arme dégainée engendrera la peur chez les villageois. En ville, les citoyens risquent même d'appeler la garde !</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e229_7Yjz</Cell><Cell>$h;WALKING$h_end;If you must follow somebody, slow down to a walk{ $toggle_run;.|.}$p;That way, you'll keep pace with them.</Cell><Cell>$h;MARCHER$h_end;Si vous devez filer quelqu'un, ralentissez jusqu'à une cadence de marche{ $toggle_run;.|.}$p;Ainsi, vous adopterez le même rythme que la personne.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e23_HnbD</Cell><Cell>$h;REPUTATION$h_end;The world notices and reacts to your behaviour.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/location_reputation.dds' width='128' height='36' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Steal someone's bread and they will not only take a dislike to you, but will also spread the dirt on you in the neighbourhood; help someone and they might be more helpful or give you a better price next time you see them.</Cell><Cell>$h;RÉPUTATION$h_end;Le monde qui vous entoure vous remarque et réagit à votre comportement.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/location_reputation.dds' width='128' height='36' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Voler quelqu'un aura pour conséquence que cette personne aura une dent contre vous et répandra des rumeurs sur vous dans le voisinage. Au contraire, si vous lui portez assistance, elle pourrait vous proposer un meilleur prix la prochaine fois que vous la croiserez.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e232_0vgh</Cell><Cell>Life in the monastery is governed by a strict daily routine. As a novice, you will be under close observation.&lt;br/&gt;If you are to work in the garden or in the library, you shouldn't wander off anywhere else.&lt;br/&gt;You'll you're somewhere you shouldn't be by the icon at the top of the screen. In such a case, you risk being punished by a Circator!</Cell><Cell>La vie monacale est régie par des règles quotidiennes strictes. En tant qu'apprenti, on va épier chacun de vos faits et gestes.&lt;br/&gt;Si vous devez travailler dans le jardin ou la bibliothèque, vous ne devez en aucun cas quitter ces lieux.&lt;br/&gt;Une icône située en haut de l'écran vous indique que vous n'êtes pas au bon endroit. Par ailleurs, vous risquez de vous faire châtier par un circateur !</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e232_bHzv</Cell><Cell>$h;TRAINERS$h_end;Some people can teach you. For some lessons you will have to know something already though. &lt;br/&gt; There might be more than one trainer for each skill, but there are always four lessons.</Cell><Cell>$h;FORMATEURS$h_end;Certains personnages peuvent enseigner. Certaines leçons nécessitent cependant d'avoir acquis des bases. &lt;br/&gt; Il existe plus d'un enseignant pour chaque compétence, mais il y a toujours quatre leçons.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e235_2CZV</Cell><Cell>$h;YOUR HOME$h_end;Rattay Mill is now your new home.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/poi_47.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22'&amp;gt; $font_color;Your bed$font_end; $p;You can sleep here and save the game. You have your own common trunk here, which is available to you in all your homes and rented lodgings.</Cell><Cell>$h;CHEZ VOUS$h_end;Le moulin de Rattay est votre nouveau logis.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/poi_47.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22'&amp;gt; $font_color;Votre lit$font_end; $p;Vous pouvez y dormir et sauvegarder la partie. Vous y disposez même d'un coffre personnel, disponible dans toutes vos maisons et chambres d'hébergement.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e238_lmPY</Cell><Cell>$h;COMBAT TRAINING$h_end;The better you get at handling a weapon, the less experience you'll get out of practicing with training weapons. Training with real weapons will be more beneficial.</Cell><Cell>$h;ENTRAÎNEMENT AU COMBAT$h_end;Plus vous saurez maîtriser une arme, moins vous obtiendrez d'expérience en utilisant des armes d'entraînement. S'entraîner avec de véritables armes s'avèrera plus bénéfique.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e238_m8jr</Cell><Cell>$h;REPUTATION$h_end;People notice your behaviour and if you really anger someone, they won't want to talk to you.$p;To put things right, try doing good deeds for others, for example.</Cell><Cell>$h;RÉPUTATION$h_end;Les gens remarqueront vos agissements et si vous finissez par mettre quelqu'un très en colère, il pourrait ne plus vous adresser la parole.$p;Pour vous racheter une conduite, essayez de faire de bonnes actions, par exemple.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e238_olV0</Cell><Cell>$h;HOME$h_end;You got yourself another home&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/poi_47.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22'&amp;gt;$font_color;Your bed$font_end; $p;You can sleep here and save the game. You also have your common chest here, the contents of which are available to you in all your homes and rented rooms.</Cell><Cell>$h;LOGIS$h_end;Vous avez obtenu un autre logis&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/poi_47.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22'&amp;gt;$font_color;Votre lit$font_end; $p;Vous pouvez y dormir et sauvegarder la partie. Vous y disposez même d'un coffre personnel, dont le contenu est disponible dans toutes les maisons et chambres que vous louez.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e241_WQjG</Cell><Cell>$h;REPUTATION$h_end;People will notice your bad behaviour and start to hate you, which means they will either attack you or run away from you.$p;A person you anger will be appeased by your imprisonment, but you can also restore your reputation, for example, by doing good deeds for others.</Cell><Cell>$h;RÉPUTATION$h_end;Les gens remarqueront votre mauvaise conduite et commenceront à vous détester et pourront, par conséquent, vous attaquer ou vous fuir.$p;Une personne en colère contre vous sera soulagée de vous savoir en prison, mais vous pouvez également redorer votre réputation en accomplissant de bonnes actions, par exemple.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e244_8YXQ</Cell><Cell>$h;DRAWING A WEAPON$h_end;Draw a melee weapon using $weapon_set1; and a range weapon using $weapon_set2;.$p;$weapon_set1; $font_color;MELEE WEAPON$font_end;$p;$weapon_set2; $font_color;RANGE WEAPON$font_end;</Cell><Cell>$h;DÉGAINER UNE ARME$h_end;Dégainez une arme de mêlée à l'aide de $weapon_set1; et une arme à distance avec $weapon_set2;.$p;$weapon_set1; $font_color;ARME DE MÊLÉE$font_end;$p;$weapon_set2; $font_color;ARME À DISTANCE$font_end;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e247_naZy</Cell><Cell>$h;LOW STATS$h_end;You're trying to use equipment that demands better abilities than you have now, so its effectiveness is greatly lowered.$p;You can find out exactly what the item demands in the $font_color;Inventory$font_end; {$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;} in $font_color;Item info$font_end; $ui_confirm;</Cell><Cell>$h;STATS FAIBLES$h_end;Vous essayez d'utiliser un équipement qui exige des capacités dont vous ne disposez pas encore. Son efficacité est donc drastiquement réduite.$p;Vous trouverez les conditions exactes pour utiliser cet équipement dans l'$font_color;inventaire$font_end; {$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;}, sous $font_color;Infos objet$font_end; $ui_confirm;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e25_ous7</Cell><Cell>$h;HEALTH$h_end;You can see your health in the red bar on the lower edge of the screen.$p;The level of health also determines the maximum level of stamina.</Cell><Cell>$h;SANTÉ$h_end;Votre jauge de santé est représentée par la barre rouge située en bas de l'écran.$p;Le niveau de santé détermine également le niveau maximal d'endurance.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e25_WP9S</Cell><Cell>The Codex{ $ui_toggle_codex;|} contains all information and points of interest about the world, including detailed tutorials.</Cell><Cell>Le Codex { $ui_toggle_codex;|} contient toutes les informations et points d'intérêts de la carte, de même que les didacticiels du jeu.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e251_gB1z</Cell><Cell>$h;TACKLE$h_end;If your opponent flees from combat, you can chase him down, grab and turn him around $attack3; giving you a chance to finish him off.</Cell><Cell>$h;PLAQUAGE$h_end;Si votre adversaire tente de s'enfuir, vous pouvez le pourchasser, l'attraper et le retourner vers vous $attack3; afin de l'achever.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e257_Ogkp</Cell><Cell>WARNING! Entering Vranik Hillfort can abort some quests in progress.</Cell><Cell>ATTENTION ! En entrant dans la forteresse de Vranik, vous risquez d'invalider certaines quêtes en cours.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e258_fqou</Cell><Cell>$h;LOW STATS$h_end;You're trying to use a bow that demands better skills than you have now, so its effectiveness is greatly lowered.$p;You can find out exactly what the weapon demands in the $font_color;Inventory$font_end; {$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;} in $font_color;Item info$font_end; $ui_confirm;.</Cell><Cell>$h;STATS FAIBLES$h_end;Vous essayez d'utiliser un arc qui exige des capacités dont vous ne disposez pas encore. Son efficacité est donc drastiquement réduite.$p;Vous trouverez les conditions exactes pour utiliser cette arme dans l'$font_color;inventaire$font_end; {$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;}, sous $font_color;Infos objet$font_end; $ui_confirm;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e259_REZr</Cell><Cell>$h;YOU HAVE NO ARROWS$h_end;For archery you need arrows!$p;If you've got some, equip them in your $font_color;Inventory$font_end; {$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;}.</Cell><Cell>$h;PAS DE FLÈCHES$h_end;Pour tirer à l'arc, il vous faut des flèches !$p;Si vous en avez, équipez-vous-en depuis votre $font_color;inventaire$font_end; {$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;}.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e260_4a2Q</Cell><Cell>$h;ROOM$h_end;Sir Hanush has rewarded you for your loyal service with a room of your own at Pirkstein!&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/poi_47.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Your bed$font_end;</Cell><Cell>$h;CHAMBRE$h_end;Le seigneur Hanush vous a récompensé pour votre fidélité en vous offrant votre propre chambre à Pirkstejn !&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/poi_47.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Votre lit$font_end;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e263_opx4</Cell><Cell>$h;TORCH$h_end;If you need a light at night, use your torch by holding $weapon_set1^;$p;Even better, use Nighthawk potion.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/999.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Nighthawk$font_end; </Cell><Cell>$h;FLAMBEAU$h_end;Si vous avez besoin de lumière la nuit, utilisez votre flambeau en maintenant $weapon_set1^;$p;Vous pouvez aussi boire une potion de l'engoulevent.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/999.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Engoulevent$font_end; </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e266_QIMA</Cell><Cell>$h;ALCHEMY$h_end;If you need another flask of Saviour Schnapps, you can buy it from a trader or at a tavern, better again an apothecary.$p;On the other hand, you can just brew it yourself in an alchemy lab.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/icon_map_alchemy.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt;$font_color;Alchemy bench$font_end;</Cell><Cell>$h;ALCHIMIE$h_end;S'il vous faut une autre flasque de schnaps du sauveur, vous pouvez en acheter auprès d'un commerçant ou dans une taverne, voire chez un apothicaire.$p;Vous pouvez aussi en fabriquer vous-même dans un labo d'alchimie.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/icon_map_alchemy.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt;$font_color;Établi d'alchimie$font_end;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e269_owBY</Cell><Cell>$h;TARGET ARCHERY$h_end;The rules of the game are simple: you shoot seven arrows, the bullseye is worth three points, the middle ring two and the outside ring one.$p;The first to finish shooting gets an extra three points!</Cell><Cell>$h;TIR SUR CIBLE$h_end;Les règles du jeu sont simples. Vous tirez sept flèches : le milieu de la cible vaut trois points, le deuxième anneau en vaut deux et l'anneau extérieur en vaut un.$p;Le premier qui a fini de tirer marque trois points supplémentaires !</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e27_WYdp</Cell><Cell>$h;INJURIES$h_end;Serious wounds to parts of the body will significantly affect your capabilities.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_torso_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' &amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_head_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' &amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_hand_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' &amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_leg_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;You can't run with injured legs, wielding a sword isn't easy with a broken arm etc.</Cell><Cell>$h;BLESSURES$h_end;Les blessures graves affecteront de manière significative vos capacités.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_torso_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' &amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_head_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' &amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_hand_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' &amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_leg_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Par exemple, vous ne pourrez pas courir avec une jambe blessée, vous aurez des difficultés à brandir votre épée avec un bras cassé, etc.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e277_qFQt</Cell><Cell>$h;GRAVEDIGGER$h_end;If you left something important in the possession of a corpse, you can find it in a trunk at the Rattay Presbytery, where the gravedigger puts the possessions of the deceased.</Cell><Cell>$h;FOSSOYEUR$h_end;Si vous avez laissé quelque chose d'important dans les affaires d'un cadavre, vous pouvez les retrouver dans une malle au presbytère de Rattay où le fossoyeur range les possessions des morts.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e282_CPJc</Cell><Cell>$h;DRYING AND SMOKING$h_end;Drying and smoking are a very useful means of preserving food for later consumption. It works the same as for cooking - simply place meat, fruit or other food in the drier or smokehouse to preserve it.</Cell><Cell>$h;SÉCHAGE ET FUMAGE$h_end;Séchage et fumage sont deux méthodes très utiles pour conserver la nourriture qu'on ne consomme pas immédiatement. Cela fonctionne comme la cuisine : placez une viande, un fruit ou tout autre aliment dans le séchoir ou le fumoir pour le conserver.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e287_Wkqy</Cell><Cell>$h;OVERLOADING$h_end;You're too overloaded to hoist yourself onto the saddle. Try dropping items or moving them to your horse's saddlebags. {$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;}</Cell><Cell>$h;SURCHARGE$h_end;Vous êtes trop surchargé pour vous hisser sur la selle. Essayez de poser des objets par terre ou de les placer dans les sacoches de votre cheval. {$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;}</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e289_eota</Cell><Cell>$h;SCARING$h_end;In order to frighten one of Fearless Felix's friends, you learned to make terrifying animal calls. Now you just need to get close enough for him to hear you.$p;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/trespass2.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt;$font_color;Fearless Fellows' Camp$font_end;$p;Then press $call_horse; You'll have to wait a while until your vocal chords are rested before grunting again.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_dog_buff.dds' width='66' height='66' align='baseline' vspace='-50' &amp;gt;$font_color;Sore throat$font_end;</Cell><Cell>$h;FAIRE PEUR$h_end;Pour effrayer l'un des amis de Felix le valeureux, vous avez appris à imiter des cris d'animaux terrifiants. Il ne vous reste plus qu'à vous rapprocher suffisamment pour être entendu$p;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/trespass2.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt;$font_color;Campement des individus intrépides$font_end;$p;Puis appuyez sur $call_horse; Vous devez attendre que vos cordes vocales soit reposées avant de rugir à nouveau.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_dog_buff.dds' width='66' height='66' align='baseline' vspace='-50' &amp;gt;$font_color;Gorge prise$font_end;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e29_6tRz</Cell><Cell>$h;BLEEDING$h_end;You are bleeding and the wound must be bandaged quickly or you will bleed to death &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_blood_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Bleeding$font_end;$p;For that you need a bandage, which you can find in your $font_color;inventory$font_end; and use on the selected body part that is bleeding &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/bandage.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Bandage$font_end;</Cell><Cell>$h;HÉMORRAGIE$h_end;Vous saignez et la blessure doit être pansée au plus vite ou vous allez vous vider de votre sang. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_blood_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Hémorragie$font_end;$p;Pour cela, il vous faut des bandages que vous pouvez trouver dans votre $font_color;inventaire$font_end; et les utiliser sur la partie du corps qui est touchée &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/bandage.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Bandages$font_end;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e291_XTpQ</Cell><Cell>$h;DOG RAN OFF$h_end;Your dog's Obedience has fallen to "$font_color;0$font_end;" and he's run off. There's nothing you can do but wait until he decides to come back to you.</Cell><Cell>$h;FUITE DU CHIEN$h_end;L'obéissance de votre chien est tombée à « $font_color;0$font_end; » et il a fui. Il n'y a rien à faire, si ce n'est attendre qu'il décide de revenir vers vous.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e295_LOiH</Cell><Cell>$h;ALARM$h_end;Your dog is now able to detect foes and their dogs. When he catches scent of them, he'll start growling, and if they're close enough, he'll turn towards them, ready to attack.$p;The higher your dog's Obedience and your Houndmaster skill, the further away he can detect foes. </Cell><Cell>$h;ALARME$h_end;Votre chien est désormais capable de détecter vos ennemis et leurs propres chiens. Dès qu'il les sentira, il commencera à grogner et s'ils sont assez proches, il se précipitera sur eux, prêt à attaquer.$p;Plus l'obéissance de votre chien et votre compétence de maître-chien sont élevées, plus il pourra détecter les ennemis de loin. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e297_vuVL</Cell><Cell>$h;SEEK$h_end;Your dog is now able to seek out interesting undiscovered places. Once he catches a scent, he'll go on ahead and lead you to them, then bark to alert you to what he's found.$p;If you can't find him, he'll soon come back anyway.</Cell><Cell>$h;CHERCHE$h_end;Votre chien est désormais capable de rechercher des lieux intéressants et cachés. Dès qu'il reniflera une odeur, il s'y rendra et vous y conduit, puis aboiera pour vous prévenir qu'il a trouvé quelque chose.$p;Si vous ne parvenez pas à le trouver, il reviendra vers vous au bout d'un moment.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e299_6eqi</Cell><Cell>$h;HUNT$h_end;Your dog can hunt nearby game. When he catches a scent of it, he'll chase it and try to take it down. The higher your Houndmaster skill, the faster he'll hunt down the game. Then he will bark to alert you that he's caught his quarry.$p;He's able to bring hares to you by himself. He won't attack domesticated animals, with the exception of enemies' dogs.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;After hunting, let your dog rest awhile. If he's too tired to hunt, you'll see the relevant debuff.</Cell><Cell>$h;CHASSE$h_end;Votre chien peut chasser le gibier proche. Lorsqu'il flairera un gibier, il va le pourchasser et tenter de l'attraper. Plus votre compétence de maître-chien est élevée, plus vite il chassera. Il aboiera alors pour vous prévenir qu'il a attrapé sa proie.$p;Il est capable de ramener seul des lièvres. Il n'attaquera pas d'animaux domestiques, à l'exception des chiens des ennemis.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Laissez votre chien se reposer après une chasse. S'il est trop fatigué pour chasser, vous verrez l'altération applicable.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e301_mEWh</Cell><Cell>$h;AGGRESSIVE DOG$h_end;You've commanded your dog to atack any nearby enemy target. Once your dog catches scent of any foe or his dog, he'll wait for nothing and attack right away.</Cell><Cell>$h;CHIEN AGRESSIF$h_end;Vous avez ordonné à votre chien d'attaquer toute cible ennemie à proximité. Dès que votre chien sentira la présence d'un ennemi ou de son chien, il se précipitera pour attaquer.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e303_RSMi</Cell><Cell>$h;HEEL$h_end;Your dog will always be next to you. He'll follow you, sticking close. He won't react to any stimuli such as an attack on you or him, but you can still give him commands by means of the interactor.</Cell><Cell>$h;AU PIED$h_end;Votre chien sera toujours près de vous et vous suivra de près. Il ne réagira à aucune provocation, comme une attaque, mais vous pourez lui donner des ordres au moyen de l'interaction.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e305_VIJp</Cell><Cell>$h;FREE$h_end;The most useful dog command. Now he will help you whenever he can. He will defend himself when attacked and help keep enemies busy. He'll run with you of his own accord, while having some freedom in deciding what to do.</Cell><Cell>$h;EN AVANT !$h_end;L'ordre le plus utile pour votre chien. Il vous aidera désormais dès qu'il le peut. Il se défendra lorsqu'il est attaqué et vous aidera à vous occuper des ennemis. Il courra avec vous s'il le veut bien, en ayant la liberté de décider de le faire.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e307_18ZE</Cell><Cell>$h;STAY$h_end;Your dog will stay put until you come back for him. You can always call him by holding $request_dog^;. He will then start walking with you, the same as if you'd given him the command $font_color;Free$font_end;.</Cell><Cell>$h;RESTE ICI$h_end;Votre chien restera en retrait jusqu'à ce que vous reveniez près de lui. Vous pouvez toujours l'appeler en maintenant $request_dog^;. Il se mettra alors à vous suivre, comme si vous lui aviez ordonné $font_color;En avant !$font_end;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e307_bOlm</Cell><Cell>$h;WARNING!$h_end;You did not succeed in surrendering!</Cell><Cell>$h;ATTENTION !$h_end;Vous n'êtes pas parvenu à vous rendre !</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e309_ViqT</Cell><Cell>$h;WARNING$h_end;Your horse's stamina is low. By pressing $sprint; you can slow to a canter. Once he's recovered a little at least, he'll be able to gallop again $horse_sprint;$horse_sprint;</Cell><Cell>$h;ATTENTION$h_end;L'endurance de votre cheval est faible. En appuyant sur  $sprint; vous pouvez réduire l'allure au petit galop. Vous pourrez de nouveau galoper lorsqu'il aura un peu récupéré $horse_sprint;$horse_sprint;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e31_tcE9</Cell><Cell>$h;BLEEDING$h_end;You're bleeding and you don't yet know how to bandage your wounds! You need to find someone who can help you!&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_blood_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Bleeding$font_end;</Cell><Cell>$h;HÉMORRAGIE$h_end;Vous saignez et vous ne savez pas encore comment panser vos blessures ! Vous devez trouver quelqu'un en mesure de vous porter secours !&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_blood_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Hémorragie$font_end;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e311_okJT</Cell><Cell>$h;COMPASS$h_end;The compass will tell you where to go in the quest you are pursuing. Just head for the active objective waypoint$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_main_quest.dds' width='66' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Go to Father.$font_end;</Cell><Cell>$h;BOUSSOLE$h_end;La boussole vous indique où aller pour accomplir la quête que vous avez entreprise. Rendez-vous simplement au point de passage de l'objectif$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_main_quest.dds' width='66' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Aller voir père.$font_end;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e313_U7oH</Cell><Cell>$h;EAT$h_end;To eat any food, pick it up. In the inventory in the tab $font_color;Food$font_end; select what you want to eat and then eat it by holding $use^; $p;{$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;}&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;$font_color;Inventory$font_color;</Cell><Cell>$h;MANGER$h_end;Pour manger de la nourriture, prenez-la. Dans l'onglet $font_color;Nourriture$font_end; de l'inventaire, choisissez ce que vous désirez manger puis mangez-le en maintenant $use^; $p;{$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;}&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;$font_color;Inventaire$font_color;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e317_7cvf</Cell><Cell>$h;IN COMBAT$h_end;When in combat, you'll see a pair of crossed golden swords under the compas.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/combat_state_1.dds' width='67' height='61' &amp;gt;$p;As long as it's active, you can't use any items from your inventory, except for changing weapons. </Cell><Cell>$h;EN COMBAT$h_end;En combat, vous verrez deux épées en or entrecroisées sous la boussole.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/combat_state_1.dds' width='67' height='61' &amp;gt;$p;Tant que ce statut est actif, vous ne pouvez pas utiliser d'objet de votre inventaire, mais vous pouvez tout de même changer d'arme. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e33_bXmS</Cell><Cell>$h;SURRENDER$h_end;Most people don't want to die, so they may surrender to you! It's then up to you what to do with them. </Cell><Cell>$h;CAPITULATION$h_end;La plupart des gens ne souhaitent pas mourir et préfèrent donc se rendre ! Il vous appartient alors de décider de leur sort. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e332_Tho9</Cell><Cell>$h;IN COMBAT$h_end;When you're engaged in combat, but the foe is at a certain distance, you'll see a pair of uncrossed silver swords under the compass.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/combat_state_2.dds' width='113' height='61' &amp;gt;$p;While it's active, you can use items from your inventory, except for changing your armour.</Cell><Cell>$h;EN COMBAT$h_end;Lorsque vous êtes engagé dans un combat mais que l'adversaire se trouve à une certaine distance, vous verrez deux épées en argent non entrecroisées sous la boussole.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/combat_state_2.dds' width='113' height='61' &amp;gt;$p;Tant que ce statut est actif, vous pouvez utiliser des objets de votre inventaire, mais ne pouvez pas changer d'armure.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e35_9h2b</Cell><Cell>$h;STEALTH$h_end;If you want to sneak in somewhere, make sure no one sees you or hears you.$p;Whether you're seen or not depends on the light and your clothing. Whether they hear you depends on the surface you're moving on and your attire, especially footwear.$p;$toggle_crouch;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;$font_color;Stealth$font_end;</Cell><Cell>$h;FURTIVITÉ$h_end;Si vous comptez vous infiltrer dans un lieu, assurez-vous que personne ne vous voie ou ne vous entende.$p;La distinction de votre présence dépend de la lumière environnante et de vos vêtements. Votre furtivité repose également sur la surface sur laquelle vous vous déplacez, votre posture et votre accoutrement, surtout vos chaussures.$p;$toggle_crouch;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;$font_color;Furtivité$font_end;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e37_92Lt</Cell><Cell>$h;DISGUISE$h_end;If you can manage to get your hands on attire belonging to a specific faction, you can infiltrate places you normally can't get into. Most important are distinctive items, such as a tabard, as well as helmets that cover the face.</Cell><Cell>$h;DÉGUISEMENT$h_end;Si vous parvenez à mettre la main sur un accoutrement appartenant à une faction spécifique, vous serez en mesure d'infiltrer des lieux en principe interdits d'accès. Les affaires les plus importantes sont celles qui sont caractéristiques à un groupe donné, comme les tabards ou les casques qui couvrent le visage.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e383_W7OM</Cell><Cell>$h;DISOBEDIENCE$h_end;Your dog's obedience has fallen and now he won't heed your commands. A graphic appears showing how long it will take before your dog will run away entirely. $p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_obedience.dds' width='66' height='66' align='baseline' vspace='-50' &amp;gt;$font_color;Disobedience$font_end;$p;When your dog is dicobedient, you can't directly give him any command except $font_color;Heel!$font_end; using $request_dog^;. But you can keep switching the commands in the dialogue.</Cell><Cell>$h;DÉSOBÉISSANCE$h_end;L'obéissance de votre chien a chuté et il ne répond plus à vos ordres. Un graphisme s'affiche, indiquant le temps avant qu'il ne finisse par s'enfuir vraiment. $p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_obedience.dds' width='66' height='66' align='baseline' vspace='-50' &amp;gt;$font_color;Désobéissance$font_end;$p;Lorsque votre chien est désobéissant, vous ne pouvez pas lui donner d'ordre, à part $font_color;Au pied !$font_end; en utilisant $request_dog^;. Mais vous pouvez changer d'ordre dans le dialogue.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e39_ubvz</Cell><Cell>$h;THEFT$h_end;If you must steal, make sure no one sees you!$p;And you need to be careful when selling stolen goods too. Try going to a trader as far away as possible from the scene of the theft, or find someone who deals in stolen goods as a matter of course - a fence.</Cell><Cell>$h;LARÇIN$h_end;Si vous devez voler, assurez-vous que personne ne vous voie !$p;Et soyez prudent lorsque vous revendez de la marchandise volée : essayez d'aller voir un commerçant se situant le plus loin possible du méfait, ou trouvez un receleur.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e396_QePo</Cell><Cell>$h;TOURNEY$h_end;The Rattay Tournament takes place once a week. You can enrol by talking to the herald in the courtyard of the Upper Castle. </Cell><Cell>$h;TOURNOI$h_end;Le tournoi de Rattay se déroule une fois par semaine. Vous pouvez y participer en parlant au héraut dans la cour du château supérieur. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e41_CnNI</Cell><Cell>$h;CRIME$h_end;If you're seen committing a crime, the local catchpoles will try to catch you. Even if you get away, people will remember your crime - the more serious the crime, the longer they'll remember.$p;You can tell by the icon to the left of the compass whether you're facing a $font_color;Fine$font_end; or $font_color;Jail$font_end;.$p;&amp;lt;.br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/crimes.dds' width='128' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;</Cell><Cell>$h;CRIME$h_end;Si l'on vous aperçoit en train de commettre un crime, les huissiers du village vont tenter de vous interpeller. Si vous parvenez à vous échapper, les gens se souviendront de votre crime — et plus le crime est grave, plus vous marquerez les esprits.$p;La peine que vous encourez est affichée par une icône située à gauche de la boussole, que ce soit face à $font_color;Amende$font_end; ou $font_color;Prison$font_end;.$p;&amp;lt;.br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/crimes.dds' width='128' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e43_4we3</Cell><Cell>$h;TRESSPASSING$h_end;If you go where you’re not supposed to, people will first warn you before calling for a guard &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/trespass2.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Warning$font_end;$p;But in guarded places they will arrest you immediately. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/trespass1.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Arrest$font_end;</Cell><Cell>$h;INTRUSION$h_end;Si vous mettez les pieds dans un lieu sans autorisation, les gens vont d'abord vous avertir avant d'appeler la garde &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/trespass2.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Attention$font_end;$p;Dans les endroits gardés, ils vous arrêteront immédiatement. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/trespass1.dds' width='64' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Arrestation$font_end;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e43_wjRV</Cell><Cell>When lockpicking, you first have to find the sweet spot with the lockpick &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/lockpicking1.dds' width='285' height='64'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; and then turn the lock {$lock_dir_fwd;|$xi_lock_dir_help;}.But that also shifts the position of the sweet spot, so you have to keep adjusting. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/lockpicking2.dds' width='285' height='128'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;If you lose the sweet spot while turning the lock, the lock will stick and you can even snap the lockpick, which emits a suspicious noise.</Cell><Cell>When lockpicking, you first have to find the sweet spot with the lockpick &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/lockpicking1.dds' width='285' height='64'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; and then turn the lock {$lock_dir_fwd;|$xi_lock_dir_help;}.But that also shifts the position of the sweet spot, so you have to keep adjusting. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/lockpicking2.dds' width='285' height='128'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;If you lose the sweet spot while turning the lock, the lock will stick and you can even snap the lockpick, which emits a suspicious noise.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e45_XI8w</Cell><Cell>When pickpocketing, it's best to search as long as possible (Figure - zoom on searching).&lt;br/&gt;Once you decide you've searched long enough, you can choose what to keep from the things you've found. Each person has his own inventory, which you will gradually discover, and the most valuable items are usually at the very bottom. Just don't forget, you have to get your hand out with the loot too!</Cell><Cell>When pickpocketing, it's best to search as long as possible (Figure - zoom on searching).&lt;br/&gt;Once you decide you've searched long enough, you can choose what to keep from the things you've found. Each person has his own inventory, which you will gradually discover, and the most valuable items are usually at the very bottom. Just don't forget, you have to get your hand out with the loot too!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e47_cKvv</Cell><Cell>$h;HUNGER$h_end;The longer you go hungry, the weaker you get, and in the end you can even die.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_hunger_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Hunger$font_end;$p;Different foods have different properties - e.g. an apple won't fill you up like a roast duck, but it will stay fresh for longer. Some foods can be more effective for healing. </Cell><Cell>$h;FAIM$h_end;Plus votre faim dure, plus vous serez faible, risquant même la mort.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_hunger_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Faim$font_end;$p;Les aliments ont des propriétés différentes — p. ex., une pomme ne vous remplira pas autant l'estomac qu'un canard rôti, mais restera consommable plus longtemps. Certains produits peuvent être plus efficaces que d'autres pour vous soigner.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e49_u4S2</Cell><Cell>$h;TIREDNESS$h_end;If you are tired, your stamina and eloquence will also gradually decrease.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_oversleep_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Tiredness$font_end;$p;Sleep is the solution. Find an available bed, which you'll recognise from the icon on the compass.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/poi_47.dds' width='60' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt;$font_color;Your bed$font_end;$p; Sit on it $use; start $sitting_sleep; and set how long you want to sleep for.</Cell><Cell>$h;FATIGUE$h_end;Si vous êtes fatigué, votre endurance et votre éloquence vont diminuer peu à peu.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_oversleep_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Fatigue$font_end;$p;Le sommeil est la solution. Trouvez un lit libre, reconnaissable à l'icône sur la boussole.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/poi_47.dds' width='60' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt;$font_color;Votre lit$font_end;$p; Asseyez-vous dessus $use;, lancez $sitting_sleep; et réglez le temps que vous souhaitez passer à dormir.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e51_DoMK</Cell><Cell>$h;SKIP TIME$h_end;If you have to wait for something, you can skip time. Press $ui_open_skiptime; and set how long you want to wait. Watch out, though - tiredness and hunger grow even during skip time.</Cell><Cell>$h;SAUT DANS LE TEMPS$h_end;Si vous êtes contraint de patienter, vous pouvez effectuer un saut dans le temps. Appuyez sur $ui_open_skiptime; et définissez la durée pendant laquelle vous souhaitez attendre. Faites attention : vous pourriez être fatigué et avoir faim après cette action.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e53_Yey8</Cell><Cell>$h;WHISTLING$h_end;You can call your horse by whistling $call_horse;.$p;But your whistle will also be heard by people within earshot, which sometimes can be a disadvantage, while on the other hand it can also be a way of distracting attention.$p;You can then mount your horse using $call_horse;</Cell><Cell>$h;SIFFLER$h_end;Vous pouvez appeler votre cheval en sifflant $call_horse;.$p;Vous serez néanmoins entendu par les personnes situées à portée de voix, ce qui peut parfois vous porter préjudice, même si cela peut aussi être un moyen pratique de diversion.$p;Vous pouvez enfourcher votre cheval en utilisant $call_horse;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e55_1cag</Cell><Cell>The basic riding controls are the same as when you're on foot. You can trot {$moveforward;$moveleft;$moveback;$moveright;|$xi_move_help;}, canter $horse_sprint; or gallop $horse_sprint;$horse_sprint;, which influences not only the horse's speed, but also reduces stamina.$p; If you try to push your horse when it's stamina is too low, it will throw you.</Cell><Cell>Les commandes de base de l'équitation sont les mêmes que lorsque vous êtes à pied. Votre cheval peut trotter {$moveforward;$moveleft;$moveback;$moveright;|$xi_move_help;}, avancer au petit galop $horse_sprint; ou au galop $horse_sprint;$horse_sprint;, ce qui influence non seulement sa vitesse, mais aussi son endurance.$p; Si vous essayez de le pousser lorsque son endurance est trop faible, vous serez désarçonné.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e57_zuui</Cell><Cell>$h;FAST TRAVEL$h_end;On the $font_color;map$font_end; {$ui_toggle_map;|$ui_open_map;} you'll see all the places you can fast travel to. Just select where you want to go and confirm.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/fast_travel.dds' width='61' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Fast travel$font_end; </Cell><Cell>$h;VOYAGE RAPIDE$h_end;Vous pouvez voir sur la $font_color;carte$font_end; {$ui_toggle_map;|$ui_open_map;} tous les endroits vers lesquels vous pouvez voyager rapidement. Il suffit de sélectionner le lieu choisi et de confirmer.$p;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/fast_travel.dds' width='61' height='64' align='baseline' vspace='-22' &amp;gt; $font_color;Voyage rapide$font_end; </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e59_V5Wz</Cell><Cell>$h;DRUNKENNESS$h_end;Alcohol begins to act gradually, giving you bonuses on Speech, Vitality, Charisma and Strength, although if you over-indulge, the after-effects can be less than pleasant. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_drunk_more_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' &amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_hangover_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' &amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_alcoholism_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' &amp;gt;</Cell><Cell>$h;ÉBRIÉTÉ$h_end;L'alcool agit progressivement. Dans un premier temps, vous obtenez des bonus d'Éloquence, de Vitalité, de Charisme et de Force. Si vous en abusez, les effets secondaires peuvent en revanche être des plus désagréables. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_drunk_more_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' &amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_hangover_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' &amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ico_alcoholism_buff.dds' width='60' height='64' &amp;gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e59_y06p</Cell><Cell>In order to brew potions, you need a knowledge of alchemy, a recipe, an alchemist's lab and the required ingredients.&lt;br/&gt;The herbarium in the lab contains all essential information about herbs and all the recipes Henry has collected. It's best to always proceed precisely by the recipe.</Cell><Cell>In order to brew potions, you need a knowledge of alchemy, a recipe, an alchemist's lab and the required ingredients.&lt;br/&gt;The herbarium in the lab contains all essential information about herbs and all the recipes Henry has collected. It's best to always proceed precisely by the recipe.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e61_BpYE</Cell><Cell>$h;HORSE$h_end;You've got your first horse. You can see its capabilities and inventory in the $font_color;Horse$font_end;{ $ui_toggle_horse;|} tab.</Cell><Cell>$h;CHEVAL$h_end;Vous venez d'obtenir votre premier cheval. Vous pouvez voir ses capacités et son inventaire dans l'onglet $font_color;Cheval$font_end;{ $ui_toggle_horse;|}.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e61_evss</Cell><Cell>The aim of the dice game is to be the first to achieve a target number of points. The players take turns and each player's turn ends when none of the dice has useful points after the throw.&lt;br/&gt;Every one and five thrown scores points, as well as three of a kind. Sometimes it pays off to surrender the points for one of the dice and throw it again with the others, so as to increase your chances of a better score.</Cell><Cell>The aim of the dice game is to be the first to achieve a target number of points. The players take turns and each player's turn ends when none of the dice has useful points after the throw.&lt;br/&gt;Every one and five thrown scores points, as well as three of a kind. Sometimes it pays off to surrender the points for one of the dice and throw it again with the others, so as to increase your chances of a better score.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e62_ICjc</Cell><Cell>$h;GUARDS$h_end;When guards challenge you to surrender, you can do so by pressing {$surrender;|$surrender_xi_modifier; $surrender_xi_activate;} if you wish to succumb to the rule of law. But decide quickly!</Cell><Cell>$h;GARDES$h_end;Lorsque des gardes vous demandent de déposer les armes, il suffit d'appuyer sur {$surrender;|$surrender_xi_modifier; $surrender_xi_activate;} si vous souhaitez vous plier à la loi. Mais décidez rapidement !</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e63_srI0</Cell><Cell>Weapons and armour become worn out and damaged with use. &lt;br/&gt;Weapons can be honed on the grinding wheel available at every good blacksmith's. To repair damaged armour, you must buy a specific repair kit&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/repairkit1.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/repairkit2.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/repairkit3.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/repairkit4.dds' width='64' height='64'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;and use it in your inventory {$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;}. For bigger repairs you'll have to go to a professional.</Cell><Cell>Les armes et armures s'usent et s'endommagent au fil du temps. &lt;br/&gt;Les armes peuvent être aiguisées sur une meule chez n'importe quel bon forgeron. Pour pouvoir réparer une armure, il vous faut une trousse de réparation&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/repairkit1.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/repairkit2.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/repairkit3.dds' width='64' height='64' &amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/repairkit4.dds' width='64' height='64'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;et l'utiliser à partir de votre inventaire {$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;}. Vous devez vous rendre chez un professionnel pour effectuer des réparations plus importantes.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e65_MZDM</Cell><Cell>$h;READING$h_end;Being able to read was a very rare skill in the middle ages and a common blacksmith's son certainly wouldn't have been literate. To understand written text, you will have to find someone who can teach you to read. </Cell><Cell>$h;LECTURE$h_end;Au Moyen Âge, il était très rare de savoir lire et un fils de forgeron ordinaire n'aurait certainement pas été alphabétisé. Pour déchiffrer un texte, vous devrez trouver quelqu'un qui puisse vous apprendre à lire. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e67_RJnl</Cell><Cell>$h;AMBUSH$h_end;You were ambushed! Fight or surrender {$surrender;|$surrender_xi_modifier; $surrender_xi_activate;}!</Cell><Cell>$h;EMBUSCADE$h_end;Vous êtes tombé dans une embuscade ! Combattez ou capitulez {$surrender;|$surrender_xi_modifier; $surrender_xi_activate;} !</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e7_eEDZ</Cell><Cell>$h;CHARACTER$h_end;By means of the first two choices in this dialogue, you will select your character's default characteristics. $p;If you're not satisfied with them, not to worry: all characteristics can be further developed without limitations. </Cell><Cell>$h;PERSONNAGE$h_end;Ce sont les deux premiers choix de ce dialogue qui vont déterminer les caractéristiques par défaut de votre personnage. $p;Si vous n'en êtes pas satisfait, n'ayez crainte : l'ensemble des caractéristiques peuvent être développées sans aucune restriction. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e79_hs14</Cell><Cell>A weapon must be honed along its full cutting edge at the right angle and with the right pressure, which you will recognise from the sparks flying. But be careful - if the weapon starts to smoke, you're exerting too much pressure and you'll damage it!</Cell><Cell>A weapon must be honed along its full cutting edge at the right angle and with the right pressure, which you will recognise from the sparks flying. But be careful - if the weapon starts to smoke, you're exerting too much pressure and you'll damage it!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e9_Gl12</Cell><Cell>$h;TO TALMBERG!$h_end;You're going the wrong way! The compass at the top of the screen always shows you which way to go.</Cell><Cell>$h;VERS TALMBERG!$h_end;Vous allez dans la mauvaise direction ! La boussole en haut de l'écran vous montre toujours quelle direction suivre.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e9_HlrL</Cell><Cell>$h;MOVEMENT$h_end;You move around using {$moveforward;$moveleft;$moveback;$moveright;|$xi_move_help;}, you can also sprint $sprint;, jump $jump;{and walk $toggle_run;|}.$p;You can interact with NPCs, items and the world using $use;</Cell><Cell>$h;DÉPLACEMENT$h_end;Le déplacement s'effectue avec {$moveforward;$moveleft;$moveback;$moveright;|$xi_move_help;}, la course avec $sprint;, le saut avec $jump;{ et marcher avec $toggle_run;|}.$p;Vous pouvez interagir avec les PNJ, les objets et le monde qui vous entourent à l'aide de $use;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e9_qHkj</Cell><Cell>Sometimes it will take a bit of persuasion to achieve your ends.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/icon_prompt_2.dds' width='40' height='40' &amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/icon_prompt_3.dds' width='40' height='40' &amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/icon_prompt_1.dds' width='40' height='40' &amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;You can rely on your eloquence, flaunt your social status, or make an impression with your strength.</Cell><Cell>Vous devrez parfois faire preuve de persuasion pour parvenir à vos fins.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/icon_prompt_2.dds' width='40' height='40' &amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/icon_prompt_3.dds' width='40' height='40' &amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/icon_prompt_1.dds' width='40' height='40' &amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;Pour ce faire, vous devrez faire appel à vos talents d'éloquence, exhiber votre statut social ou impressionner avec votre force.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e92_H8h7</Cell><Cell>$h;SURRENDER$h_end;If it looks like you are about to die in combat, you can always yield!{$surrender;|$surrender_xi_modifier; $surrender_xi_activate;}$p;However, there's no guarantee your opponent will accept your surrender. </Cell><Cell>$h;CAPITULATION$h_end;Si les choses tournent mal au combat, vous pouvez toujours vous rendre !{$surrender;|$surrender_xi_modifier; $surrender_xi_activate;}.$p;Cependant, il n'est pas dit que vous adversaire accepte votre reddition. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap14_sch29_yLmT_e98_JtR3</Cell><Cell>You're overloaded, so you move more slowly and can't fast travel, run or jump. Try dropping some inventory items or putting them in your horse's saddlebags.{$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;} </Cell><Cell>Vous êtes surchargé et par conséquent, vous vous déplacez plus lentement et ne pouvez effectuer de voyage rapide. Essayez d'abandonner des objets de votre inventaire ou placez-les dans la sacoche de votre cheval.{$ui_toggle_inventory;|$ui_open_inventory;} </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap16_sch14_aKwr_e196_RNHd</Cell><Cell>From now on you can come to the arena anytime and challenge the master to a training duel.</Cell><Cell>Vous pouvez à partir de maintenant revenir à l'arène quand vous le voulez pour défier le maître à un duel d'entraînement.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap16_sch14_aKwr_e334_Z6Pt</Cell><Cell>Slash {$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;} three times in a pattern:&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src="img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor0.dds" width="80" height="70"&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src="img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor2.dds" width="80" height="70" &amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src="img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor3.dds" width="80" height="70"&amp;gt;</Cell><Cell>Taille {$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;} enchaînement trois fois de suite :&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src="img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor0.dds" width="80" height="70"&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src="img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor2.dds" width="80" height="70" &amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src="img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor3.dds" width="80" height="70"&amp;gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap16_sch14_aKwr_e337_X4mm</Cell><Cell>If you time your block right at the start of the window of opportunity for a perfect block:&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursorPerfectblock.dds' width='79' height='74'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;you'll execute a master strike with an automatic riposte! As you increase your proficiency in combat, your chances of executing a master strike will significantly increase.</Cell><Cell>Il faut effectuer votre parade pile au début de la marge allouée pour réussir un blocage parfait :&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursorPerfectblock.dds' width='79' height='74'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;vous réaliserez alors un coup de maître avec une riposte automatique ! Au fur et à mesure que vous améliorerez vos compétences au combat, vous aurez davantage de chance d'effectuer un coup de maître.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap16_sch14_aKwr_e445_OGoT</Cell><Cell>If you time your block right at the very start of your opponent's swing, instead of a perfect block, you'll execute a master strike with an automatic riposte! As you increase your proficiency in combat, your chances of executing a master strike will significantly increase.</Cell><Cell>Si le timing de votre parade tombe pile au début de la frappe de votre adversaire, à la place d'une parade parfaite, vous réaliserez alors un coup de maître avec une riposte automatique ! Au fur et à mesure que vous améliorerez vos compétences au combat, vous aurez davantage de chances d'effectuer un coup de maître.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap16_sch14_aKwr_e447_7JRL</Cell><Cell>If you want Bernard to teach you new techniques, you'll have to beat him in combat first.</Cell><Cell>Si vous voulez que Bernard vous enseigne ses techniques, vous devrez d'abord le battre.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch9_DLO7_e490_54B4</Cell><Cell>Time to shoot!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Pick up the bow by pressing '1'&lt;br&gt; Wait for the order, then draw the bow using the left mouse key and release at the right moment.&lt;br&gt; Aim at the centre!</Cell><Cell>C'est l'heure de tirer!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Saisissez l'arc en appuyant sur '1'&lt;br&gt; Attendez les ordres, tirez ensuite avec l'arc à l'aide du bouton gauche de la souris et relâchez au bon moment. &lt;br&gt;Visez le centre de la cible!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch9_DLO7_e491_dHal</Cell><Cell>Time to shoot!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Pick up the bow by pressing '1'&lt;br&gt; Wait for the order, then draw the bow using the left mouse key and release at the right moment.&lt;br&gt; Smaller logs carry higher points!</Cell><Cell>C'est l'heure de tirer!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Saisissez l'arc en appuyant sur '1'&lt;br&gt; Attendez les ordres, tirez ensuite avec l'arc à l'aide du bouton gauche de la souris et relâchez au bon moment. &lt;br&gt;Les plus petites bûches rapportent plus de point!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e39_csE7</Cell><Cell>Treasures of the Past DLC activated.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt;You were surprised to find out that among other things in your chest there are several curious drawings. They are adorned by an archaic seal attesting to the noble and ancient origin of its issuer. It appears that the drawings describe places where some exquisite armour is hidden.</Cell><Cell>Le DLC trésors du passé est activé.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt;Vous avez eu la surprise de découvrir dans votre coffre d'étranges croquis. Le sceau primitif qui a été apposé dessus témoigne de leur origine noble et ancestrale. Il semblerait que ces dessins indiquent les lieux où une superbe armure a été dissimulée.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e503_nXVC</Cell><Cell>If you accuse him now and the accused is innocent, it will negatively affect your reputation in the region. However if you let a murderer go free, the unsolved murder will make the locals angry.</Cell><Cell>If you accuse him now and the accused is innocent, it will negatively affect your reputation in the region. However if you let a murderer go free, the unsolved murder will make the locals angry.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e15_vKGI</Cell><Cell>Surrender ($surrender;), to pay your way out of a fight</Cell><Cell>Capituler ($surrender;), pour payer et ainsi éviter un combat.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch2_iRf2_e1571_ibfX</Cell><Cell>The game is saved automatically at the important moments of the quests; every time you get some sleep and when you leave the game. To be able to save the game at any time, you´ll need Schnapps. Once you drink it, Quicksave option is created. At the same time you get a bit drunk though; at the beginning drinking Schnapps will have a rather positive effect but higher amounts will be negative for you; you can even become a drunk, so be careful with it. There are three slots for Quicksave and Schanpps will always rewrite the oldest one.</Cell><Cell>La partie est sauvegardée automatiquement lors des moments importants des quêtes, à chaque fois que vous dormez et lorsque vous quittez le jeu. Pour pouvoir sauvegarder quand vous le souhaitez, il vous faut du schnaps. Après l'avoir bu, une sauvegarde rapide est créée. Au début, le schnaps a des effets positifs, mais il vous rend aussi un peu ivre et à forte dose, il devient néfaste. Vous pouvez même devenir alcoolique si vous en abusez. Les sauvegardes rapides disposent de trois emplacements et le schnaps écrase toujours le plus ancien.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e183_Lnit</Cell><Cell>In combat you are locked onto your opponent.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;You can move around him using {$moveleft; and $moveright;|$xi_move_help;}.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;You can unlock from your opponent at any time by holding $sprint;</Cell><Cell>En combat, votre adversaire est verrouillé.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Vous pouvez vous déplacer autour de lui en utilisant {$moveleft; et $moveright;|$xi_move_help;}.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Vous pouvez le déverrouiller à tout moment en maintenant $sprint;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e184_Y9Xq</Cell><Cell>Blocking&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Hold $block; to block.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;You will automatically parry your opponent's strikes at the cost of stamina. When you don't have enough stamina to deflect a foe's strike, you'll be hit. While blocking, your stamina regenerates more slowly.</Cell><Cell>Parade&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Maintenir $block; pour parer.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Vous bloquez automatiquement les coups, ce qui fait baisser votre endurance. Si vous n'avez plus assez d'endurance pour parer, vous êtes touché. Quand vous parez, votre endurance se régénère plus lentement.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e186_gnRz</Cell><Cell>{$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;}  - Slash (strong attack)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Choose the direction of your strike using {mouse|$xi_zone_help;}&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor0.dds' width='80' height='70'&amp;gt;</Cell><Cell>{$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;} - Taille (attaque puissante)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Choisissez la direction du coup porté avec {la souris|$xi_zone_help;}&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor0.dds' width='80' height='70'&amp;gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e187_RB2A</Cell><Cell>$attack2;  - Stab (weak attack)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Weak attacks tend to be faster and more precise at the cost of force.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Stabs can be aimed at the face (upper zone) or at the body (any other zone).</Cell><Cell>$attack2; - Estoc (attaque faible)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Les attaques faibles sont en général plus rapides et plus précises au détriment de la force.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Les coups d'estoc peuvent être portés au visage (zone supérieure) ou au corps (autre zone).</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e188_89pz</Cell><Cell>You can chain strikes together into a combo.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Start a new strike as soon as the previous one ends. You can change the attack zone or strike repeatedly. Try to press {$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;} or $attack2; at the very moment the previous strike lands.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt; The window of opportunity is between striking at the opponent and the end of the swing.</Cell><Cell>Vous pouvez enchaîner les attaques pour réaliser une combo.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Lancez une attaque dès que la précédente s'achève. Vous pouvez changer la zone d'attaque ou enchaîner des coups successifs. Essayez d'appuyer sur {$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;} ou $attack2; pile au moment où votre coup frappe l'adversaire.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt; Le timing idéal se trouve entre la toute fin de la frappe et l'impact.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e189_XxQv</Cell><Cell>Stamina&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Stamina powers your attacks and shields you. You need stamina to attack and deplete it by blocking your foe's strikes. When you don't have enough stamina for blocking, you will be wounded.</Cell><Cell>Endurance&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;L'endurance donne de la puissance à vos attaques et vous protège. Il vous faut de l'endurance pour pouvoir attaquer, et vous en perdez en parant les coups de l'ennemi. Si votre jauge d'endurance n'est pas assez remplie pour pouvoir effectuer une parade, vous serez blessé.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e191_o4uJ</Cell><Cell>When your armour fully deflects a hit, you only lose stamina. But if your stamina is low or your armour is weak at the point of impact, you will also lose health.</Cell><Cell>Si votre armure dévie entièrement un impact, vous ne perdrez que de l'endurance. Mais si votre jauge d'endurance est basse ou si votre armure comporte un point faible sur la zone d'impact, vous perdrez aussi de la santé.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e192_DH1Y</Cell><Cell>Perfect Block&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;To fully deflect an adversary's strike, you need to time your block into it. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursorPerfectblock.dds' width='79' height='74'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Press $block; as soon as the strike starts to perform a Perfect Block that doesn't cost any stamina and gives you a chance to follow up with a quick counter-strike - riposte.</Cell><Cell>Parade parfaite&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Pour dévier entièrement le coup d'un adversaire, il faut réaliser sa parade avec un timing parfait. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursorPerfectblock.dds' width='79' height='74'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Appuyez sur $block; dès que l'attaque est lancée pour réaliser une parade parfaite qui ne coûtera pas d'endurance et qui vous donnera l'opportunité de riposter.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e192_EF2T</Cell><Cell>It's important to direct your attack where it hurts most.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Use {your mouse|$xi_zone_help;} to change zone:&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor0.dds' width='80' height='70'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor3.dds' width='80' height='70'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Your opponent's chance of blocking is less when you strike at unguarded zones.</Cell><Cell>Il est essentiel de diriger son attaque vers les zones les plus critiques.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Utilisez {la souris|$xi_zone_help;} pour changer de zone :&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor0.dds' width='80' height='70'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor3.dds' width='80' height='70'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Lorsque vous visez les zones les plus vulnérables, il sera plus difficile pour votre adversaire de réussir une parade.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e193_2Mvw</Cell><Cell>Block now!</Cell><Cell>Appuyez sur parer !</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e197_LfDZ</Cell><Cell>Simply blocking strikes isn't the best defence. Later you'll learn some useful tricks.</Cell><Cell>Se contenter de parer n'est pas le meilleur moyen de se défendre. Vous apprendrez plus tard de nouvelles astuces.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e199_69l7</Cell><Cell>Final Showcase&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Now just fight for a while to practice what you've learned. You can come back to the training ground later to improve your skills.</Cell><Cell>Démonstration finale&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Maintenant, combattez un peu pour mettre en pratique ce que vous avez appris. Vous pourrez revenir plus tard sur le terrain d'entraînement afin de perfectionner votre technique.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e234_DeVH</Cell><Cell>Prepare to strike by holding {$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;}. Then change zone and release the strike.</Cell><Cell>Préparez votre attaque en maintenant {$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;}. Changez ensuite de zone et relâchez.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e235_exIz</Cell><Cell>Dodging: move to the side or back at the very moment your foe attacks.</Cell><Cell>Esquive : effectuez un pas de côté ou en arrière au moment même où l'ennemi lance son attaque.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e236_rrcN</Cell><Cell>Try to attack from the side the opponent will find harder to block in time.</Cell><Cell>Essayez d'attaquer là où l'adversaire aura le plus de mal à parer à temps.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e237_91vz</Cell><Cell>Move now!</Cell><Cell>Allez-y !</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e238_QnFk</Cell><Cell>Archery&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Draw your bow using $weapon_set2;.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Hold {$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;} to load an arrow, release it to shoot.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Watch your stamina!&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt;You can abort shooting and save your arrow using {$attack_abort_mouse;|$attack_abort;}</Cell><Cell>Archerie&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Dégainez votre arc avec $weapon_set2;.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Maintenez {$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;} pour encocher une flèche et relâchez pour tirer.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Surveillez votre Endurance !&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt;Vous pouvez annuler le tir et conserver votre flèche avec {$attack_abort_mouse;|$attack_abort;}.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e242_SCXh</Cell><Cell>Attack your trainer to see the technique.</Cell><Cell>Attaquez votre formateur pour voir la technique.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e243_UCH8</Cell><Cell>Free fight! Show what you've learned so far.</Cell><Cell>Combat libre ! Faites une démonstration de ce que vous avez appris jusqu'à maintenant.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e367_Olfw</Cell><Cell>You succeeded in your first chain strike.</Cell><Cell>Vous avez exécuté votre premier enchaînement d'attaques avec succès.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e386_wCfs</Cell><Cell>{$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;}  - Slash (strong attack)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Choose the direction of your strike using {mouse|$xi_zone_help;}</Cell><Cell>{$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;}  - Taille (attaque puissante)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Choisissez la direction du coup porté avec {la souris|$xi_zone_help;}</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e387_qFdv</Cell><Cell>$attack2;  - Stab (weak attack)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Weak attacks tend to be faster and more precise at the cost of power.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Stabs can be aimed at the face (when you're holding your sword in a high guard) or to the body (any other guard).</Cell><Cell>$attack2;  - Estoc (attaque faible)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Les attaques faibles sont en général plus rapides et plus précises au détriment de la force.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Les coups d'estoc peuvent être portés au visage (quand vous tenez votre épée en garde haute) ou au corps (avec toute autre garde).</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e388_bxNL</Cell><Cell>It is important to direct your attack where it hurts most.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Use {your mouse|$xi_zone_help;} to change your stance and attack different zones.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Your opponent has less chance of blocking when you aim your strikes at zones unguarded by his weapon or shield.</Cell><Cell>Il est essentiel de diriger son attaque vers les zones les plus critiques.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Utilisez {la souris|$xi_zone_help;} pour changer de garde et attaquer différentes zones.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Votre adversaire a moins de chances de parer vos coups quand vous visez les zones non couvertes par son arme ou son bouclier.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e389_gz41</Cell><Cell>Perfect Blocks&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;To fully deflect an adversary's strike, you need to time your block into it. Press $block; as soon as the strike starts to perform a Perfect Block that doesn't cost any stamina! You can also follow up a Perfect Block with an immediate strike to perform a Riposte.</Cell><Cell>Parades parfaites&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Pour dévier entièrement le coup d'un adversaire, il faut réaliser sa parade avec un timing parfait. Appuyez sur $block; dès que l'attaque est lancée pour réaliser une parade parfaite qui ne coûtera pas d'endurance ! Vous pourrez aussi faire suivre une parade parfaite d'une riposte immédiate.</Cell></Row>
</Table>