<Table>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch2_iRf2_e1571_ibfX</Cell><Cell>The game is saved automatically at the important moments of the quests; every time you get some sleep and when you leave the game. To be able to save the game at any time, you´ll need Schnapps. Once you drink it, Quicksave option is created. At the same time you get a bit drunk though; at the beginning drinking Schnapps will have a rather positive effect but higher amounts will be negative for you; you can even become a drunk, so be careful with it. There are three slots for Quicksave and Schanpps will always rewrite the oldest one.</Cell><Cell>The game is saved automatically at the important moments of the quests; every time you get some sleep and when you leave the game. To be able to save the game at any time, you´ll need Schnapps. Once you drink it, Quicksave option is created. At the same time you get a bit drunk though; at the beginning drinking Schnapps will have a rather positive effect but higher amounts will be negative for you; you can even become a drunk, so be careful with it. There are three slots for Quicksave and Schanpps will always rewrite the oldest one.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e183_Lnit</Cell><Cell>In combat you are locked onto your opponent.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;You can move around him using {$moveleft; and $moveright;|$xi_move_help;}.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;You can unlock from your opponent at any time by holding $sprint;</Cell><Cell>Під час бою ви зафіксовані на супротивнику.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Ви можете рухатися навколо нього, використовуючи {$moveleft; and $moveright;|$xi_move_help;}.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Ви можете зняти фіксацію в будь-який момент, утримуючи $sprint;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e184_Y9Xq</Cell><Cell>Blocking&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Hold $block; to block.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;You will automatically parry your opponent's strikes at the cost of stamina. When you don't have enough stamina to deflect a foe's strike, you'll be hit. While blocking, your stamina regenerates more slowly.</Cell><Cell>Блокування&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Утримуйте $block; для блокування ударів.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Ви автоматично парируватимете удари вашого супротивника за рахунок витривалості. Якщо у вас бракує витривалості, щоб відбити удар ворога, вас поранять. Коли ви блокуєте удари, витривалість відновлюється повільніше.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e186_gnRz</Cell><Cell>{$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;}  - Slash (strong attack)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Choose the direction of your strike using {mouse|$xi_zone_help;}&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor0.dds' width='80' height='70'&amp;gt;</Cell><Cell>{$attack1_mouse;|,$attack1;}  — рублячий удар (сильна атака)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Виберіть напрямок удару за допомогою {mouse|$xi_zone_help;}&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor0.dds' width='80' height='70'&amp;gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e187_RB2A</Cell><Cell>$attack2;  - Stab (weak attack)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Weak attacks tend to be faster and more precise at the cost of force.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Stabs can be aimed at the face (upper zone) or at the body (any other zone).</Cell><Cell>$attack2;  — укол (слабка атака)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Слабкі атаки, як правило, швидші та точніші.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Уколи можна спрямовувати в обличчя (верхню зону) або тіло (будь-які інші зони).</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e188_89pz</Cell><Cell>You can chain strikes together into a combo.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Start a new strike as soon as the previous one ends. You can change the attack zone or strike repeatedly. Try to press {$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;} or $attack2; at the very moment the previous strike lands.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt; The window of opportunity is between striking at the opponent and the end of the swing.</Cell><Cell>Ви можете зв'язувати удари в комбінацію.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Починайте новий удар одразу, як закінчується попередній. Ви можете постійно змінювати область атаки чи тип удару. Спробуйте натиснути {$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;} чи $attack2; у той самий момент, як попередній удар досягає цілі.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt; Вдалим для цього є момент після того, як удар досяг супротивника, але перед тим, як рух зброї завершився.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e189_XxQv</Cell><Cell>Stamina&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Stamina powers your attacks and shields you. You need stamina to attack and deplete it by blocking your foe's strikes. When you don't have enough stamina for blocking, you will be wounded.</Cell><Cell>Витривалість&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Витривалість підсилює ваші атаки та захищає вас. Вона потрібна, щоб нанести удар, і також витрачається під час блокування ударів противника. Якщо у вас бракує витривалості, щоб блокувати удар, вас поранять.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e191_o4uJ</Cell><Cell>When your armour fully deflects a hit, you only lose stamina. But if your stamina is low or your armour is weak at the point of impact, you will also lose health.</Cell><Cell>Коли ваші обладунки повністю відбивають удар, ви втрачаєте лише очки витривалості. Але якщо рівень витривалості низький або ви пропустили удар в область, де обладунки слабкі, ви також втратите очки здоров'я.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e192_DH1Y</Cell><Cell>Perfect Block&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;To fully deflect an adversary's strike, you need to time your block into it. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursorPerfectblock.dds' width='79' height='74'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Press $block; as soon as the strike starts to perform a Perfect Block that doesn't cost any stamina and gives you a chance to follow up with a quick counter-strike - riposte.</Cell><Cell>Досконалий блок&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Щоб повністю відбити удар супротивника, потрібно вгадати з моментом блоку. &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursorPerfectblock.dds' width='79' height='74'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Натисніть $block; одразу, як починається удар, щоб поставити досконалий блок, який не коштуватиме вам ані очка витривалості та дасть шанс провести швидку контратаку — удар у відповідь.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e192_EF2T</Cell><Cell>It's important to direct your attack where it hurts most.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Use {your mouse|$xi_zone_help;} to change zone:&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor0.dds' width='80' height='70'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor3.dds' width='80' height='70'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Your opponent's chance of blocking is less when you strike at unguarded zones.</Cell><Cell>Важливо спрямовувати ваші атаки туди, де вони завдадуть найбільшої шкоди.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Використовуйте {your mouse|$xi_zone_help;}, щоб змінити область:&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor0.dds' width='80' height='70'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/ccursor3.dds' width='80' height='70'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Шанси вашого супротивника заблокувати удар зменшуються, якщо бити в незахищені області.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e193_2Mvw</Cell><Cell>Block now!</Cell><Cell>Блокуйте!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e197_LfDZ</Cell><Cell>Simply blocking strikes isn't the best defence. Later you'll learn some useful tricks.</Cell><Cell>Просто блокувати удари — не найкраща стратегія захисту. Пізніше ви навчитеся деяким корисним хитрощам.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e199_69l7</Cell><Cell>Final Showcase&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Now just fight for a while to practice what you've learned. You can come back to the training ground later to improve your skills.</Cell><Cell>Заключна вправа&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Поспарингуйте, щоб відпрацювати отримані знання на практиці. Пізніше ви можете повернутися на майданчик, щоб покращити свої навички.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e234_DeVH</Cell><Cell>Prepare to strike by holding {$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;}. Then change zone and release the strike.</Cell><Cell>Приготуйтесь ударити, утримуючи {$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;}. Потім змініть зону та нанесіть удар.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e235_exIz</Cell><Cell>Dodging: move to the side or back at the very moment your foe attacks.</Cell><Cell>Ухилення: пересуньтеся вбік або назад безпосередньо в момент атаки супротивника.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e236_rrcN</Cell><Cell>Try to attack from the side the opponent will find harder to block in time.</Cell><Cell>Спробуйте атакувати з тієї сторони, з якої супротивнику важче поставити вчасний блок.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e237_91vz</Cell><Cell>Move now!</Cell><Cell>Рухайтеся!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e238_QnFk</Cell><Cell>Archery&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Draw your bow using $weapon_set2;.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Hold {$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;} to load an arrow, release it to shoot.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Watch your stamina!&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt;You can abort shooting and save your arrow using {$attack_abort_mouse;|$attack_abort;}</Cell><Cell>Стрільба з лука&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Витягніть лук, використовуючи $weapon_set2;.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Утримуйте {$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;}, щоб накласти стрілу, і відпустіть ці кнопки, щоб вистрілити.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Слідкуйте за рівнем витривалості!&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt;Ви можете передумати робити постріл і зберегти стрілу, використавши {$attack_abort_mouse;|$attack_abort;}</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e242_SCXh</Cell><Cell>Attack your trainer to see the technique.</Cell><Cell>Атакуйте свого вчителя, щоб зрозуміти техніку.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e243_UCH8</Cell><Cell>Free fight! Show what you've learned so far.</Cell><Cell>Довільний спаринг! Покажіть, чому ви вже навчилися.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e386_wCfs</Cell><Cell>{$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;}  - Slash (strong attack)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Choose the direction of your strike using {mouse|$xi_zone_help;}</Cell><Cell>{$attack1_mouse;|$attack1;} — рублячий удар (сильна атака)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Виберіть напрямок удару за допомогою {mouse|$xi_zone_help;}</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e387_qFdv</Cell><Cell>$attack2;  - Stab (weak attack)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Weak attacks tend to be faster and more precise at the cost of power.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Stabs can be aimed at the face (when you're holding your sword in a high guard) or to the body (any other guard).</Cell><Cell>$attack2; — укол (слабка атака)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Слабкі атаки, як правило, швидші та точніші.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Уколи можна спрямувати в обличчя (коли тримаєте меча у верхньому положенні) або тіло (з будь-якого іншого положення).</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e388_bxNL</Cell><Cell>It is important to direct your attack where it hurts most.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Use {your mouse|$xi_zone_help;} to change your stance and attack different zones.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Your opponent has less chance of blocking when you aim your strikes at zones unguarded by his weapon or shield.</Cell><Cell>Важливо спрямовувати ваші атаки туди, де вони завдадуть найбільшої шкоди.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Використовуйте {your mouse|$xi_zone_help;}, щоб змінити стійку та атакувати різні області.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Шанси вашого супротивника блокувати удар зменшуються, коли ви б'єте в зони, не захищені його зброєю чи щитом.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch39_RQYJ_e389_gz41</Cell><Cell>Perfect Blocks&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;To fully deflect an adversary's strike, you need to time your block into it. Press $block; as soon as the strike starts to perform a Perfect Block that doesn't cost any stamina! You can also follow up a Perfect Block with an immediate strike to perform a Riposte.</Cell><Cell>Досконалий блок&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Щоб повністю відбити удар супротивника, потрібно вгадати з моментом блоку. Натисніть $block; одразу, як починається удар, щоб поставити досконалий блок, який не коштуватиме вам ані очка витривалості. Після досконалого блоку ви можете провести швидку контратаку — удар у відповідь.</Cell></Row>
</Table>